I see a large IPO on the horizon.
You're surrounded by journals. Watch
your position.
Overnight success.
The place 3000
double
right
misinformation.
Quarter clearing order inbound.
>> Let's just roll.
We are surrounded by journal. Hold your
position.
Come. Get up.
Trust the experts here.
Five. Focus.
We are
founder
code.
I see multiple journalists on the
horizon. Stand by.
UAV online.
Blaze.
Double blaze.
Triple blaze.
Double kill.
Fight.
Wrong.
Cup is
win.
>> Team deathmatch.
We are experts.
triple blade
just
right
clearing order inbound.
We are surrounded by journalists. Hold
your position.
>> Strike one.
>> Strike two.
Activate golden retriever mode.
Marky clearing order inbound.
>> Five good.
I see multiple journalists on the
horizon.
You're watching TVPN. Today is
Wednesday, March 25th, 2026. We are live
from the TVP Ultra, the temple of
technology, the fortress of finance, the
capital of capital,
>> sorry, ramp.com. Time is money. Save
both. Easy. Use corporate cards, bill
pay, accounting, and a whole lot more
all in one place. Uh, we have a great
show for you today, folks. We got Mike
from Arc Prize coming on.
>> The Nupinator.
>> He did it. He did it. Uh we'll talk
about this later. We have Nathan, my
buddy from Air Street Capital, Rohan
Dar, uh tell giving us an update on
what's happening in San Francisco in the
housing market. Eric Jorgensson, the the
the author of the book of Elon's coming
on. And then Jenny just from Peak Six
Investments coming on later. Thank you
so much to tuning in for tuning in
today. Um linear of course is the system
for modern software development. 70% of
enterprise workspace on linear are using
agents. So um there's been a debate uh
truth bomb dropped by Emil Michael. He
says forgiving benchmark and others
would be like letting the Wuhan
Institute of Urology slide back into a
good reputation because the new senior
manager of pandemic causation has made
more friends than his predecessor. And
so this got me thinking and I'm probably
going to have to put on the steel helmet
for this one because this is waiting
into dangerous territory defending
benchmark. But my question is how close
are we to actually being able to to uh
forgive Benchmark? When is the right
time? It's been a decade. Uh obviously
the the drama between Benchmark and
Travis Kalanick was was awful. I think
everyone's against what happened. Uh but
the question is like is like what is a
what is a venture firm? It is its
partnership. If the partnership turns
over at some point like is it a new is
it a new team? Do you get a second shot?
Can you can you actually change uh
change the reputation? And so um believe
me like I I get the benchmark criticism
like Travis is truly a generational
entrepreneur and was on such an amazing
run, right? So he was
>> Jason Jason from Saster was reacting to
our interview with Travis and uh his
take which I totally agree with is
>> it's hard to if Travis had stayed in the
role it's hard to imagine Uber being
worth less than something like a
trillion dollars today.
>> Yes. So uh our friend of the show on
McCabe over at in.ai
and Intercom uh said uh Whimo is
superior to Uber in literally every way.
This was a year ago in March 25th
actually to the day a year ago he said
this in uh Whimo superior to Uber in
literally every way that matters to
consumers smoother safer more reliable
no chatty weird rude rude drivers
private quiet self-driving car services
are going to dominate their human driver
incumbents and own says uh TBT when I
think that's throwback two right
throwback to when benchmark pushed
Travis out of Uber and canned the
self-driving division that he started
literally 10 years ago and so uh this is
this This is what's so so tricky about
this is that, you know, Uber survived.
It's 150 billion market cap. It's bigger
than when Travis was ousted, but getting
a 2x over a decade is not what I think
people were expecting from Uber under
Travis's leadership. Uh it's and has
fallen to just 5 billion. like he won
the capital war and Dar has done a great
job managing the business but I feel
like a lot of the success of Uber has
been built on the foundation that Travis
set up. It wasn't a complete
reinvention. If anything, they just hone
down the core business.
>> And the thing that the thing that is
holding the business back right now, at
least from a valuation standpoint, is
this big question, right, around
self-driving,
>> how, you know, and and DAR has has
answered this question, you know,
thousands of times. Right now the
strategy is to invest in self-driving
companies, partner with self-driving
companies, but not the same as like
having, you know, having
>> developed their own internal IP and
product starting a decade ago and seeing
where that would have been
>> by now
>> is is just rough.
>> Hard to think about.
>> Yeah. And so Uber is valued at 150
today, something like that. Uh Whimo uh
was valued in February of this year at
126 billion. And so yes, Whimo's been
working on self-driving longer, but you
have to imagine that there's another 50
billion of market cap. You have a
serious
>> what would Whimo be valued
>> if Travis was the CEO, right? You would
get some type of Travis premium on it.
just
>> just the market would be would would say
totally totally totally totally you have
this sort of one of one entrepreneur in
the seat
>> 100%. Uh and and just to sort of recap
uh where things stand I mean Shervin
Pishavar been been on the show as well.
We've had like everyone from this saga
in the TVPN orbit uh both Travis and
Bill Gurley have been on the show.
Shervin's been on the show. Emil
Michael's been on the show. We've uh
we've we we've talked to a number of
people that have been around this this
story and it's a fascinating one. It's
one of the most interesting. It was
certainly formative in my career because
I got to Silicon Valley and this was the
first big story that played out really.
Uh so Shervin said, "In my opinion,
Gurley single-handedly destroyed
hundreds of billions in value. Travis
and Emil staying in charge of Uber would
have led to a Teslasized win 500 billion
plus for everyone including Benchmark's
LPs. He nuked decades of Benchmark's
reputation with founders. the market has
spoken and no future Travis Quality
founder would ever touch him or his
former firm again, especially since
three of the partners that approved of
the ousting of of Travis are still at
the firm. And so my question is like how
many partners need to be at the firm
until we can call this a ship of Thesus.
So for those who uh are not up to speed
on their Greek mythology, in Greek
mythology, Thesus is the mythical king
of the city of Athens. He rescues the
children of Athens from King Minos after
slaying the Minotaur, which is his
mythical beast. Uh, and then he escapes
onto a ship going to Delos. Each year,
the Athenians would commemorate this
success by taking the the ship on a
pilgrimage to Delos in to honor Apollo.
Over time, because they're sh they're
sailing the ship every year, uh, various
of its timbers rotted and were replaced.
A question was raised by ancient
philosophers. If no pieces of the
original ship remained in the current
ship, is it still the ship of Thesus? If
it was no longer the same, when had it
ceased existing as the original ship?
So, some people might say 50/50. Some
people might say, "Yes, it is it is the
the the same ship because replacing one
board at a time, the ship is the
concept." And you can swap everything
out 25 times, it's still the same ship.
Uh it there isn't like a it's a it's a
paradox. There is no like right answer.
It's a philosophical question, but it
applies, I think, to benchmark because
back when uh Kalanick resigned as Uber
CEO on June 20th of 2020 uh 2017
uh after investor impressure after
investor pressure that included
Benchmark. Uh on that exact date,
Benchmark's equal GP roster was Bill
Gurley, Eric Visra, Matt Kohler, Mitch
Laski, Peter Fenton, Sarah Tavl. Today,
the partnership has changed
dramatically. The only two that remain
are Peter and Eric. And you have uh
Chattton, Ev Randall, and Jack Alman uh
who are new to the partnership post the
Uber scandal. And so it's not a full
ship of thesis, but only onethird of the
original 2017 partnership remains. And
my question for those who remain
reluctant to forgive Benchmark is like
what happens if Peter and Eric retire or
leave at some point and the full ship of
Thesius is complete? Like maybe you'll
shift.
>> Yeah, right now. Right now 40% of the
40% of the partnership was there
>> 33%. Oh, I mean I guess two out of the
five. Yeah. So two two out of the five
because they've added three but only
onethird of the original partnership
remains.
>> The question is did uh Chatan, Everett,
and Jack come in and as part of the
interview process say like you're
absolutely right. I mean to defend Evo
two out of the three
>> I E had just graduated from college like
he was truly like not involved in the
Uber scandal and yet uh you know people
will visit upon him
>> knowing Everett and Jack uh I'm sure I'm
sure
>> during the interview process they were
like I I you know the storied firm
>> I'm excited to join but we can never do
we can never do anything like that again
and so and so one one question that's
worth asking is like it's like is the
firm that did this
>> and ultimately
>> it you know stained this this storied
brand
>> and has certainly suffered the
consequences right they've put up in you
know incredible returns
>> uh since then but I'm sure they've
missed a lot of deals that would have
made their returns even better because
of that kind of narrative around the
firm and so they have they I would say
>> uh you know Emil Michael and others are
upset that they're doing great deals at
all.
>> Yeah.
>> But I think it is uh
>> that a question I have is like are they
if
>> if they're in a situation again, right,
in the same situation kind of situation,
are they more what what decision are
they more or less likely to make, right?
I would I would argue like they are
probably less likely to
>> I would think so
>> go against the founder given given how
this entire situation has played out.
>> Yeah. Yeah. The only the only steel man
and this is this needs the full steel
helmet because it's so hard to steel man
the benchmark thing but the full
steelman of the benchmark thing. It's
really bad. It's really bad to bench I'm
sorry for everyone. I'm sorry. Uh but
it's basically that uh every partner at
benchmark it's an equal partnership. So
every partner was going to make a clean
$1 billion. They were all going to be
billionaires from this one deal. And it
was such a power law that that like
there was no path to becoming a
billionaire for you know from the other
from the other investments most likely.
And so you see the endless 247 hit piece
pile stack up and you got Mike Isaac,
you know, bloodhounded on at the New
York Times writing books. They're
turning into movies. Like it's getting
rough. It's getting rough.
>> Mike Mike Isaac's at your door.
>> Yeah, Mike Isaac's at is at the door.
the barbarians are at the gate and
you're like, I'm either a billionaire or
I'm going back to a poultry 10 million
and I can't I can't do that. I can't do
that. And so they freak out and they're
like, we got to salvage this thing. We
got to just push it out in the public
markets. We got to get out of this name.
And so uh they basically just it's just
too nerve-wracking. And uh yeah, it's
not a strong steel, man. But I think I
think that's a little bit more of what
happened than than like taking a stand
on like oh like this particular thing
that happened was so egregious. It was
more just like okay like wow all my
money like 99% of my net worth is in
this asset and it's looking like it
could be a zero because Lyft is coming
from behind. There's a whole bunch of
VCs they're p piling into that. The
narrative is totally flipping. there's a
boycott Uber campaign like and
everyone's like ah like what's going on?
I gotta get out of this. I I I I gotta
salvage this. And I think that was maybe
more of the underpinning than like like
I I I'm I'm taking some sort of like
moral stand on a particular hit piece or
something like that. Uh anyway, it's
rough. Uh but fortunately, you know,
ship the process, maybe it happens. I
don't know. Would Delian accept that
argument? Probably not. Would Emil
probably not. But uh they're not making
it any easier with the Manis investment
either because the like like there was a
world where it was like okay yeah the
Uber thing happened a decade ago the
partnership is basically entirely new
and they're focused on
>> but it's but but
>> it's not there yet. Yes.
>> It's just not there yet.
>> It's not there yet. But still there I
think you can rewrite this in 5 years.
>> Yeah. you yeah you made this point that
this is it's too early to call this but
>> directionally given that the firm is
still is still putting up great returns
they've gotten to a bunch of
>> uh great companies over the last five
years
>> uh I think we are on p on a path to the
to the to the benchmark
>> well yeah
>> being the venture ship of thesis
>> and uh VC Brag said Airbnb has no homes
Uber has no cars and Benchmark has no
partners of course That was an
exaggeration. Uh but they did get down
to just three partners which is very
very small for uh for a venture capital
firm. Uh some some have dozens of
partners. Um but different strategy and
we will see where it goes. Anyway, let
me tell you about app loving profitable
advertising made easy with Axon.ai. Get
access to over 1 billion daily active
users and grow your business today. And
let me also tell you about Lambda.
Lambda is the super intelligence cloud
building AI supercomputers for training
inference that scale from one GPU to
hundreds of thousands. Uh, so Sora, rest
in peace, Sora. The app is leaving.
>> Ev is in the chat.
>> There he is.
>> Class of 17 represent.
>> Yes. Yes. E was Ev was chugging beers
while Uber was getting ousted. Do not
visit the the the sins of the father on
the son. That's what I would say. Ev not
guilty.
>> E was Ev was a boulder.
>> Yeah, he was hanging out. He was having
>> What happened senior year? What
happened?
I I I think I think uh I think EB A E A
E A E A E A E A E A E A E A E A ED
deserves a fair shake and should not and
should not have to bear the bear the
cross from
>> the question the real question do do E
and Jack pull a benchmark and force out
>> the original partners
>> they don't have the legal control to do
so but neither did they during the Kalin
>> at at this point Ev is probably already
getting uh getting calls from Sequoia to
come be the senior steward you know
because He's he's he's on a meteoric
ride.
We're really all over the place today.
Uh anyway, Sora is now is it still in
the app store? I think it's like the
announcement was that it will be leaving
the app store.
>> Millions of people have made content on
the app. You have to leave it running
for some amount of time.
>> There's a phase out, but the
announcement happened and now it is is
going out. And there's I have a bunch of
takes on this. Um, obviously this is not
the end of video creation for OpenAI.
This will be rolled into chatbt, I
imagine. Um, Tyler uh Hodgej put it
well. Bullish killing products quickly
is hard. Almost no one can do it. It's a
good sign for OpenAI. They're
consolidating in in many ways. It's like
last week you heard about like the red
the the code red was like a month or two
ago and then it was like we're
refocusing and then it's like here's
step one of refocusing like a single app
that we're going to push everything
together. Um and also I just I've I've
enjoyed making some videos in Sora. I've
never enjoyed having to go to a separate
app. I want all of that to live in one
place. So that makes a lot of sense. Uh
let's see what Dax said. It's lame to
see all the people saying ha I called
it. I knew Sora wouldn't work. Yeah,
duh. Because everyone thought everyone
thought that, including me who were
working on it. Uh uh they probably
learned a lot trying to make it work
anyway for every successful thing that
exists. A hundred efforts like this had
to fail and those learnings are fed into
making something that ultimately does
work and provides you with a steady
paycheck. Yes. It's interesting because
um this this quote of like people
saying, "Ha, I called it. I knew Sora
would work." That is not how I
interpreted the vibes around the Sora
launch. Like I went back and revisited
the essay that I wrote on October 1st.
We had the slop versus farming debate. I
was really on a tear back then. Said
slop is bad. We the timeline don't want
to be pigs at the trough. We don't like
it when tech leaders treat us like farm
animals, but we love farming. Farming is
lindy. We the timeline want to return to
a world where we are filling up troughs
with slop on a daily basis, I guess. So
between Google Deep Mind, Meta Super
Intelligence, and OpenAI, we now have
three different variations on AI video
products, each met with slightly
different responses. So the yeah, the
interesting thing here is that like uh
Google has been like charging ahead,
launching it, it's in it's in real, it's
in uh shorts. Uh and that's just been
like not a story at all. What was
interesting was that the the vibes
around both Meta Vibes and Sora were
like this is going to oneshot humanity.
They're like this is going to be too
successful. That was it was like
>> it was it was like a entertainment doom
loop. Exactly. You you could imagine
exactly
>> it just getting so good at generating
the next thing that you would want to
see better than even a billion humans on
Instagram
>> Yes.
>> could do. And
>> that's not what we've seen.
>> Yes.
>> So far.
>> And so like my big question was was like
will this actually be sticky? Will
people like this? And at what rate? I
mean, I read I read LLM generated text
daily, but I also read a ton of not LLM
generated text. And my my ratio has
grown exponentially. Uh, but it hasn't
gone to 100%. Nowhere near it. Like
probably 5% of the text that I read is
LLM.
>> I mean, it we should actually revisit
how we were processing it during launch
when it was, you know, rocketing.
>> We should just throw on that three-hour
stream and just watch that and react to
how our jokes were that day. But uh even
at the time I remember saying very
obvious that they built like a very cool
creative tool. Yeah.
>> And uh they have the potential to seed a
network with this. There's all this you
know novel content. They had they had
allowing creators and
>> you know people like Sam to uh allow
people to use their their IP. Yeah. Uh
it was very very well executed launch
but even from the beginning it was like
okay obviously cool creative tool it's a
totally different ball you know this
like come for the tool stay for the
network has been like an enduring
>> strategy right Chris Dixon probably
wrote that in like 2014
maybe or like a long time ago over 10
over 10 years ago
>> uh but just because you build a tool
that is attached to a network like that
jump is just really really really really
tough
>> especially when there are three or four
five serious networks that are at scale
that can on day one support the format
of the file that is produced from the
model. So in a world where
generative AI video came out not in a
MP4 file or anov file. It came out in
some sort of format that could never be
uploaded to Instagram reels. then you
have a chance to build a network and run
away with it. And this was the story of
Instagram like like Instagram just had
better support for images than Facebook
did. And then Vine had support for video
literally before Instagram. So Instagram
it was like I have a video on my phone.
It's cool. I want to share it. Yeah.
>> Sharing it to Instagram was not
possible. Now on day one you generate an
AI video. You want to share it? You can
share it on Tik Tok.
>> Yeah. It's just the incentive. If you
create if you created an amazing video
on on
>> Sora,
>> what is the most logical thing to do? If
you're a creator and you want reach,
post it to Instagram. There's just
naturally there's billions of people
there there were millions of people on
Sora and a lot of energy and momentum.
>> Yeah. Um,
>> and it's not lost on me that the same
day that Sorro was killed, uh, you have
a viral breakout reality TV style
series, uh, show putting up incredible
numbers on TikTok for uh, Fruit, Love
Island, I believe it's called. It's an
AI generated uh, twist on Love Island.
Uh, there's romantic intrigue and plot
lines and stories and consistent
characters and a lot of things that have
come from a variety of AI models. And we
we we should talk to the person that's
that's the entrepreneur behind that
project because I would be interested to
know what the stack is because I imagine
it's not just, you know, going to a
single Gen AI app. I imagine that they
have a whole pipeline of of like a
workflow in place to actually generate
that. And so we're at this weird moment
where you know Sora the app is going
away, but we're also seeing more and
more AI generated content slowly see
success. Whether that's the podcast
that's at the top of the charts that's
fully AI generated. Uh there's this Love
Island show. There's a number of niches
where they've found the right product
market fit for AI generated content. But
it's not overnight we're living in
infinite jest and we just can't look
away. It's like for specific things
>> it makes a lot of sense and so it's
working there.
>> Interesting to think about Google's
strategy with with video. Even even
Google was like we cannot operate this
for free at scale.
>> 250 bucks a month. I
>> No, that was the that was the discounted
rate.
>> Oh, I think I'm at 500 a month or
something.
>> It was like an entry to start it was
like $250 a month
>> and it was brutally weight limited like
>> Yeah. Even even with we were we were
laughing at this because
>> three a day
>> it I remember we'd be like at the gym in
the morning you would fire off a couple
prompts
>> and and then you were like
>> I hope I got it right.
>> Yeah. Wouldn't get it right. Then you
were rate limited and you're like wait
I'm rate limited
>> on a on a $250 plan that's going to jump
to 500. You're probably paying Got to
check the rate check our is probably
paying 500 a month still.
>> No, seriously. and and that and that
that's Google with
>> all this cash flow
insane data advantage with YouTube
>> and and that let me tell you rate limits
kill retention like nothing nothing is
worse if you're in Instagram the endless
scroll exists Tik Tok you can you can
scroll endlessly you can use the imagine
if Tik Tok was like after five minutes
you have to close the app and come back
in 20 minutes like how successful do we
think that would be it would be a
disaster And that was the experience for
both Sora and V3 where you would fire
off a prompt and it would be like okay
come back in a couple minutes going to
take me a while to cook and then and
then you fire off five and it's like
okay no more for today like and then and
then you the next day happens and you
forget about it and you and you go on
something else. So clearly the compute
constraints are are immense and there's
just so much more value value that can
come from enterprise and can come from
deep research and so many of the other
models that are immediately economically
valued like codegen like enterprise
workflows and it's maybe more boring and
less viral uh and less controversial but
it's it's where the compute needs to go
and so I think you're going to see the
chips be moved around inside of all the
labs to like compute will find the most
optimal output. Like the tokens of the
most value will always be the ones that
it flow that the compute flows to. And
as a lot of people predicted like just
endless random generations that aren't
quite dialed yet, even the best video
models like they're just not there. They
require a lot of work. Uh is not the
same as as where we are in terms of
knowledge retrieval, where we are in
terms of codegen. It's just way more
valuable. So anyway, let me tell you
about Octa. Octa helps you assign every
AI agent a trusted identity. So you get
the power of AI without the risk. Secure
every agent. Secure any agent. Thank you
guys. And let me also tell you about
Cisco.
Critical infrastructure for the AI era.
Unlock seamless real-time experiences
and new value with Cisco.
>> Market clearing order inbound.
>> What did they say?
>> September people overestimate how much
brain rod happens in a year and
underestimate how much brain rod happens
in a decade. So yes.
>> Yes.
still.
>> So, I mean, I'm using brain rot
poratively there, but uh but I do think
that like this this move does not really
bend the curve of of just AI generated
content, but I still think it's like a
slow roll out. Like it's it's fast in
the sense that like we went from no slop
on the timeline to lots and we went from
like like actually zero. There was like
one one cool AI video Harry Potter
Balenciaga was like entertaining to
general people and now we get like five
and then we get like next year we'll get
like 20 and then eventually it'll be
like hundreds and it'll be like oh yeah
I'm actually into that. Like people are
into cartoons and people are into CGI
movies and superhero movies and pe some
people will be into it. Some people will
never like it. Some people will always
say I want a black and white film from
the ' 40s. That's what I want to watch.
uh and and and these rollouts, the
diffusion of this stuff will happen.
Should we revisit uh one of
>> Sweet Davidson says,
>> "What what is this?"
>> Y'all are worried about the wrong open
claw.
>> This is a good post.
>> This is the open claw that uh that F.
Randall was worried about in 2017. He
was not He was not thinking about
>> was Whiteclaw invented in 2017. When did
Whiteclaw get founded? That's a great
That's a great I feel like it it really
took off. It had a fast takeoff.
>> Yeah. 2016.
>> 2016. Okay. Very good chance he was an
early adopter.
>> He might have been an early adopter of
OpenClaw. It truly was. Uh
Open uh I'm calling it OpenClaw now.
Whiteclaw did have a fast takeoff for
sure. It went from 0 to 60 and it was
just everywhere all of a sudden. Uh
anyway, uh let me tell you about Sentry.
Centry shows developers what's broken,
helps them fix it fast. That's why
150,000 organizations use it to keep
their apps working. I got a story for
you, Jordy. Today, as I was driving into
Hollywood from my hometown of Pasadena,
I was driving through Hollywood and I
look over and there is a new Hollywood
sign. I'm not kidding about this. The I
I actually saw this. I took a picture. I
can maybe send it into the chat, but I
can just show you because I'm driving
and I just see this like
>> Billy Bowman. Billy Bowman. I don't
know. I I I'll send it into the to the
chat so they can pull it up. Uh let me
see. Production. Here we go. But anyway,
uh it is a uh it is a remarkable story
because Fiverr is running a one of the
coolest out ofome campaigns like just
from an out ofome inventory. I didn't
know you could do this. Let's uh we can
pull up either my picture or we can pull
up
>> let's pull up this video from KTLA 5.
>> KTLA 5 had a video breaking down what's
going on. Let's watch this and then
we'll react to this. And while the team
pulls that up, I'm going to tell
everyone about Labelbox, RL
environments, voice robotics, eval, and
expert human data. Labelbox is the data
factory behind the world's leading AI
teams. So, let's pull up the uh KTLA 5
report uh about uh AI coming for
Hollywood, the mysterious sign along the
101. underneath a logo for Fiverr and a
search box that says, "Find the best AI
directors." It's a brash, bold
statement. AI
>> bold state for Hollywood. Fiverr has
made a name for itself, connecting
projects with freelancers. Now, they're
launching an AI video hub, which they
say can make content at a fraction
compared to traditional production. This
Billy Bowman guy is one of the directors
that you can hire. He's based in Sweden.
He's made AI videos for Google,
Universal Music Group, and others. As
you know, AI really hasn't taken over
Hollywood yet, but it has certainly
crept into commercials. Brands like
Google and Jeep rolling out AI on
national campaigns. Many are slowly or
slowing rather to see the 30-foot sign
which went up over the weekend. I first
noticed it stuck in traffic yesterday
morning after someone was so entranced
they rear ended somebody else. It's
causing accidents.
>> So interesting. AI director. Yeah. Yeah.
>> So, it's basically someone who puts the
prompt into the machine and chooses
>> is Fiverr going to pay the prompt in the
box, buddy.
>> Fender bender.
>> That's a great question. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Can they be held liable
>> for such a distracting sign? I
>> thought you know
flush with money. Whether or not it is a
bubble like you can debate.
>> That's interesting because Fiverr is not
one of those companies.
KTLA 5 is not prepared for it not to be
a bubble.
>> Uh so Fiverr's market cap now is $560
million. Uh and that's down about 95%
over the last 5 years.
>> Where are you seeing that? I'm seeing
350.
>> Sorry. Yeah. 359. What did I say?
>> 500.
>> Oh, sorry. So it's a $360 million
company today. Down 95% from uh from 5
years ago. Uh it started selling off in
2021 uh sort of pre-Chad GPT. So I think
the AI narrative might be a little bit
overblown there. It did IPO um around
this price. It was a $700 million IPO I
think uh maybe a billion dollars. Uh
went through a massive boom during COVID
and then uh and then sold off. Uh but of
course the AI wave has not been kind to
Fiverr because a lot of the tasks like
you know generating
>> AI is very very very good at $5 creative
work $25. Obviously the prices go well
beyond $5 since uh since since the early
days but in terms of the kind of
projects that I always use Fiverr for AI
just oneshots all of that
>> and the nature of Fiverr is like you
have to define your task in a prompt.
It's not it's not oh have like a long
conversation, get drinks with somebody.
>> That was often that was often the the
bottleneck. That was the bottleneck. It
was like, okay, I need to do this task.
I I need like 10 minutes to like
properly define it all these things. And
it's honestly way more time than you
spend prompting normally. Because with
prompting, you're just like, I'll just
try it a few times.
>> Bunch of times,
>> kind of iterate,
>> hit my rate limits, and then fire back
up. Yeah. I mean, it was always a
bottleneck when I remember as an
entrepreneur, I found out about Fiverr
and I was like, this is amazing. I can
get random stuff done for five bucks,
but the time commitment, actually
finding the right person, making sure
the reviews are good, it it wound up
being like hours of work, and if you
have a consistent flow, you're better
off just hiring a person. So, the the
So, they got kind of squeezed in the
middle.
>> Yeah. The market is is not excited about
Fiverr right now. They're being valued
basically at four times IDA.
>> Okay.
>> Uh and uh so, yeah,
>> this is an interesting pivot for them.
They're basically saying that uh you can
come to us to hire someone who has all
the tooling set up to actually sit there
and and sort of you know nanny all the
AI models because it is a hassle like
you as you described with me in V3 I was
sitting there like okay I fire off four
prompts then I go back like it's way
better if you if you're on the API and
you have Higsfield wired up and you have
you know runway ML and you have access
to the Chinese model seance you know,
the right tool for the job and then you
do fine-tune on someone's face. There's
a whole bunch of things that you can do
to get better results, but it takes time
and it's a hassle and it's more of a
professional job. It's not actually out
of work.
>> Here's here's the main problem with the
campaign.
>> Yes.
>> Is that Billy Bowman
>> is a real person, okay,
>> with his own website, with his own
Instagram. you can just go and
like the primary issue with with uh
these labor market places like Fiverr is
disintermediation.
>> If you uh if if a business hires
somebody on Fiverr and has an amazing
experience, eventually they're just
going to go direct because they build up
a lot of trust and it's very different
than than a platform like Uber where you
don't necessarily want the same driver
every time because they're not around
you and all these things. And so the
reason that that that the the Fiverrs
and the Upworks of the world and and
there's been a bunch of other like
engineering focused marketplaces just
have never reached like insane scale
like Uber is because of the
disintermediation and this campaign is
effectively an ad for Billy Bowman who
you could just go hire today.
>> Yeah, disintermediation has always been
a problem on these platforms. Anyway,
let's move on. Uh let me but first let
me tell you about Finn.AI, the number
one AI agent for customer service. If
you want AI to handle your customer
support, go to finn.ai. And let me also
tell you about the New York Stock
Exchange. Want to change the world?
Raise capital at the New York Stock
Exchange. Uh, speaking of stocks, uh,
did you see that Bombardier, the
manufacturer of private business jets,
is down 10% over the past month. A lot
of people were wondering why this was
happening. I think we now know why, and
it's probably because the shot across
the bow from United Airlines. So, what
competes with a private jet? Potentially
United Airlines new product, which is an
entire row of economy seats. We got to
pull this up. United Airlines says, "The
entire row is all yours. Welcome to the
United Relax Row. Three adjacent United
Economy seats with adjustable leg rests
that can be raised or lowered to create
a cozy, lie flat space for stretching
out. You'll also get a mattress pad,
blanket, and two pillows. If you're
traveling with kids, a plushy, too.
United Relax row will be available
starting next year on more than 200 of
the 787s and 777s,
each with up to 12 of these brand new
rows. So, what do you think, Jordy? Is
this the way I was telling Tyler
Cosgrove, who is out of the studio
today, he's in uh Washington, DC, he's
got to demo this. He's got to get on one
of these. I don't know. Every time an
airline announces something, it's always
like 5 years until it actually is
available. I've been waiting for
Starlink for a long time. Took a long
time for that to get rolled out from the
PR release.
>> United has pretty good pace. Haven't
they been quick to
>> Do you think Tyler could get on this
tomorrow
>> or today? He's going to the airport
today.
>> I think I think if Tyler's resourceful
enough, he could just if he ended up in
a row, two empty seats next to him, he
could just figure out a way to detach
>> the armrest blocking this. Yeah.
>> And just kind of kind of build your own.
>> Yeah.
>> He might they might have to land the
plane and arrest him. Yeah. but
potentially worth the risk.
>> He could also he could also potentially
negotiate with whoever's sitting next to
him say, "Hey, you go and spend the
entire flight in the lavatory and in
exchange I will vibe code you a sloppy
app of which I don't understand what
programming language is used.
>> I'll trade you an app for your seat.
>> I'll trade you an app for your seat."
And somebody might be like, "That's
amazing. I don't have anyone that can
vibe code for me. This is This is too
good." No, I'm sorry. Ryan Peterson
says, "Now we just need to put stairs on
the food drink cart so you can climb
over the top of them to get to the
bathroom instead of holding."
>> Yeah, this just this just feels like
this just feels very very chaotic.
>> But this is this is wild.
>> Good.
>> I don't know. Starlink, a relaxed row, a
dream. I I think that this could be a
good option. Uh, United built a product
that everyone who has been who has ever
been on a plane wanted, says John
Collison.
>> John, you need to work on fixing
Bombardier's stock price.
>> I don't think it's related. Oh,
apparently Air New Zealand launched this
in 2010. I wonder
>> No, it is related because he he should
he should help them build out their
pipeline.
>> Well, he's he's just pumping his bags
because he owns a uh a property in
Ireland. How do you get there? You got
to fly on United. So, you know, one hand
washes the other on this. He's he's he's
talking his own book. No, just kidding.
Let me tell you about console.com.
Console builds AI agents that automates
70% of IT, HR, and finance support,
giving employees instant resolution for
access requests, and password resets.
And let me also tell you about Railway.
Railway is the all-in-one intelligent
cloud provider. Use your favorite agent
to deploy web apps, servers, databases,
and more, while Railway automatically
takes care of scaling, monitoring, and
security. And
>> Carter says, "If you say no to pretzels,
the flight attendant should give you
something called a coin of restraint
while worth nothing now. These coins
will play a major role in the afterlife.
The coin of restraint is very, very
good." I like that. Uh well, Elon Musk
is teasing something cooler than a
minivan that might come because uh Elon
said the Cybertruck rear bench has three
seats of ISOIX attachments and is wide
enough to fit three child seats or three
adults. So, there's been a big debate on
uh the ISOIX attachments. These are the
little metal uh hooks that are installed
in every car in the back seat for for
child seats. And so child seat
requirements mean that you have to have
a car that has these and it's been uh
it's been called like the death of the
five kid family or something like that
or like the death of the big family
because at a certain point in order to
have another kid you have to upgrade
your car and that has an expense
associated with it. you need a three row
SUV or you need a minivan or you need
something bigger that's not as that's
not as affordable as you know just a
normal sedan that used to be able to
just throw four kids across and maybe
that was less safe
>> regulation killed the birth rate
>> people people actually say this people
say that uh that child seats have saved
like like a million lives but then
they've stopped 10 million from being
born they they they talk about the
relative exchange ratios I haven't
really dug into it too much but um
there's clearly demand for more spacious
vehicles with more seating. The Model S
used to come with a third row, which I
still don't understand how that was
possible. Um, the Model X came with a
third row and there was uh and in China
they actually sell a Model Y L which is
a long wheelbase version of the Model Y.
I hope they bring that to the space.
>> People are saying make a minivan Elon
Elon says something way cooler than a
minivan is coming.
>> What do you think it is?
>> And people are speculating. Garcia here.
>> I think it might be a data center. uh
test.
>> I think you might be like, "There's
another data center coming."
>> Chip Fab.
>> Yeah, Chip Fab. He's like, "You
>> you're gonna be able I'm gonna and and
and Texas is gonna change the child
labor law so that
>> instead of worrying about bringing your
kids around to different places, no,
they're in the fat. They're in the clean
room.
>> They're in the clean room.
>> They're fully suited up.
>> Suited up.
>> They're making chips." No, people are
speculating. This is very cool. Uh Genai
has been amazing for car enthusiasts to
create basically their own concept cars.
Yeah, these look very very cool.
>> I mean, it's funny because make a Tesla
that look make a Tesla version of the
Rivian.
>> Yeah,
>> because it looks exactly like it. But
let's let's get into some of the
speculation. So,
>> okay. What what are people saying?
>> Cia Banister says an RV.
>> Uh, that could be fun. Uh, Arthur
McWater says, "I can't wait for the next
Roadster unveil." Elon was teasing, it
was on Joe Rogan, right? This concept of
maybe it'll fly. And I think what Elon
could be could be getting at is
>> uh picture picture picture a roadster.
>> Not a great family car.
>> Hard to put kids in a in a sports car.
Some of them you technically can, but
it's so uncomfortable and kind of
chaotic. Very few people would.
>> And I think what we could see is the
Roadster comes with five uh kind of
like, you know, that Fury collaborative
combat aircraft from Andre. What if it
comes with like up to five little mini
roaders? Roadsters that can that are
just trained to autopilot behind the
primary roadster. So you can be in your
sports car and then however many kids
you have are in the mini drones
following that fun.
>> And uh
>> what about a what about a Chinook heavy
lift uh helicopter with two massive
rotors that can lift your roadster off
the off the ground? Yes.
>> Technically a flying car then.
>> Yes. Anyway, let me tell you about
phantom cash. Fund your wallet without
exchanges or middlemen and spend with a
Phantom card. Um, I have a question for
you, Jordy. Are you are you running the
new AI model? It's on co-work. It's
literally on co-pilot. You can probably
find it on codeex, dude. It's on
co-author. It's a co-sign exclusive.
It's on cocaine. You can run it on
cocaine. You can literally go to cocaine
and run it. Uh, what a great copy pasta.
This is one of the funniest uh funniest
formats. Uh but yes, the war for
co-pilot and co-work is heating up. Uh
we got to find a new term. I think uh
people have been really really fighting
neck.
>> Well, I was telling uh Microsoft they
should they just name it Coco.
>> Coco.
>> Microsoft co-pilot coowork. It's just
Coco.
>> Coco would be good. There's a few
different there's a few different
options. Uh I do I think I prefer the
nonthropomorphized
AI names although they are a little bit
colliding in the name space. I have been
a fan of uh of you know the the the
codeexes and co-works and co-pilots.
Those feel more collaborative to me and
they feel more like tools than the Bards
and the and the series and the Alexexas
and the Roffus and the Sparkies like
that that's just a different uh vibe.
And I think that uh I if we're living in
a world where people are going to form
uh you know strong relationships with
these tools uh introducing them truly as
tools is probably
>> Let's uh see what's going on with QVC.
>> Okay,
>> let's pull up this video.
>> And we also have one of our guests
joining early at 11.
>> No, he's he's he's going to be joining
uh he'll be ready to join in in an hour.
>> Are you sure?
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Uh, let's check the production
team because I've already I've already
texted. Okay, cool.
>> We'll continue for the next 15 minutes.
>> Fantastic. Well, take us through the
next story. What do you want?
>> Uh, Q River says, "Que basically
reinvented live streaming decades.
Invented live streaming decades ago.
Ghost 247." They invented live TV. Uh,
Ghost 247. A good 80% of the show is
just the host going on long personal
digressions. People watch it as
background. Heavy parasocial element.
Hosts know the callers. 95% of repeat
buyers. It's 100% Twitch for grandmas.
Let's pull up QVC.
>> And with the submarine,
>> I wanted to tell you that I got that
peasant blouse with the tassels.
>> Yes.
>> And I used to wear the tassels on my
pasties.
Do you know what pasties are?
>> This is
>> Okay.
>> Ridiculous.
>> Do you know what what pasties are?
>> Let me I'm going to
>> Okay. Well, I have on to move on.
>> We're moving on. Let me tell you about
11 Labs.
Build intelligent real-time
conversational agents. Reimagine human
technology interaction with 11 Labs. And
let me also tell you about Gemini 3.1
Pro. We are going to deep dive ArcGI
today. And Gemini 3.1 Pro has done very
very well with a more capable baseline.
It's great for super complex tasks like
visualizing difficult concepts, the
synthesizing data into a single view or
bringing creative projects to life. Uh
SpaceX aims to file IPO as soon as this
week. Uh I know everyone is excited for
the S1. Uh particularly I think people
will be focused on XAI. Yeah. What they
have going on. I think that uh I think
>> are they going to have to break it out
in the in the S1?
>> I would assume the first time we
actually see the economics of inference,
the economics of a foundation lab. Even
though yes, they are at a smaller scale.
hard to read too much into it because
they've been investing so far ahead of.
>> Yeah. I I just think that like there is
a world where we get broken out
financials that you can dig through and
you can understand based on Grock
pricing which we see and topline revenue
and cost. We can actually see are they
serving that model profitably and there
will be you know a lot to dig into
there. Obviously the other labs have
different strategies, different vertical
integration points, different economics,
different pricing regimes. I mean the
the the the true frontier, the the
models that are are are dominating ARKGI
uh which we will talk about in 15
minutes. Um those command a premium, a
price premium uh and and and there's a
wild difference between charging 15
bucks per million tokens versus $2 per
million tokens. So uh it will be
>> Yeah. If you and if remember it was I
think it was in Q4 of last year if you
looked on open router Gro was what had I
think it was like Grock fast
>> had a a ton of usage people are like
okay why is this happening and part of
it at least I believe was because they
were subsidizing it
>> well
>> um but okay so here here's what I think
so so people were posting this as though
it was fact uh but I think uh I think
it's a very real possibility So, uh, I
think Elon will will will try to aim for
the company to actually go out on on
April 20th, 420.
>> Really?
>> Um, and I think it is possible if he
goes
>> fast.
>> The the ticker, we'll see what the
ticker ends up being, but I think some
people would like knowing Elon's very
millennial sense of humor, I think the
ticker se is
>> Oh, you think so? plus the yeah April
20th IPO. I I would assume that
>> you think this is a real prediction.
You're not trolling.
>> I'm not saying I'm not saying I would
bet on it, but I think there's like a I
think there's I think there's
>> I I would put the the April 20th at at
maybe like, you know, 30% and then the
ticker maybe down at at 15%.
>> Calli has when will SpaceX officially
announce an IPO? before June 1st, which
April 20th would be before June 1st.
>> I'm not talking about I'm talking about
like list actual like listing day,
>> like the day of the IPO.
>> Yeah, this is just announcing the IPO,
>> which I don't even know if they
>> they haven't even confirmed this. This
is now this is currently in in the scoop
uh in the scoop thing. So, they haven't
even
>> scoop you said
>> they So, the
>> Wait, John, did you say scoop?
>> Yes, this is a scoop from from
>> What is What is this?
>> From scoop doggy dog.
>> Can we go to the wide angle? We got
Katie roof scoop master.
>> We have a new award her the first TVN
golden scoop.
>> The golden scoop award.
>> Do you want to show her the the
>> I don't want to I don't want to pick it
up yet.
>> Why not?
>> Okay, we can we can show we we need to
give the golden scoop award for the best
scoop of the day to Katie Roof who moved
markets with her scoop. She of course is
the deputy bureau chief of venture
capital at the information and she's an
absolute scoop athlete. She's scoop
doggy dog and and she moved markets. So,
uh, SATS is up 7.8%. BKSY
is up 4.8%. Uh, Lunr is up 4.1%. Every
stock in the space and
>> we're working on a new award award show,
the Scoopies.
>> The Scoopies.
>> The TVPN Scoopies.
>> I think Katie Roof is a lock.
>> I mean, she's in she's she's a front
runner for sure.
>> Putting on a generational run.
>> Front runner for sure. Yeah. It's so
it's so funny the the uh I mean
incredible moment for the retail space
investor community.
>> Yeah.
>> Because they're just for some reason
people people
>> um anytime you get SpaceX repricing
they're like well this
>> this other random company that happens
to be technically on the same market map
definitely deserves to be worth 7% more.
>> Yeah. I don't know. I I I I I was as
skeptical uh about the the rest of the
lunar economy for a long time. It felt
like winner take all. It felt like
SpaceX was running away with it. Um but
there have been interesting dynamics
where where companies that are buyers of
SpaceX capacity, whether on the
satellite internet side or on the launch
capacity side, they don't want a
monopoly to exist. And so they're
willing to throw money at competitors.
And Jeff Bezos has stuck around with
Blue Origin. Rocket Lab's done very
well. There's been a bunch. Uh people
are saying we need to redesign
the scoop. I don't know what you're
talking about.
>> I don't even know what you what you
could be talking about.
>> It's an ice cream scoop. It's an ice
cream scoop that people get your mind
out of the gutter. Head over to Shopify.
Shopify is the commerce platform that
grows with your business and lets you
sell in seconds online, in store, on
mobile, on social, on marketplaces, and
now with AI agents.
>> Okay. Casey Hammer is worried.
>> What is he saying?
>> He's worried.
>> Why is he worried?
>> He's stressed.
>> Why is he stressed?
>> What I worry about is a generation of
talented, experienced engineers being
too rich to work. So, if you're worried
about being demotivated by your
incredible SpaceX liquidity, you have to
do what I recommend, which is the
Brewers Millions approach, where you
have to spend all the money in 30 days
without telling anyone why you're doing
it. This is from the 1980s, 1990s
comedy, uh, called Brewster Millions,
which I highly recommend you watch. uh
in it uh a man is is gifted an
inheritance from a wealthy uh uncle or
father figure, grandfather and uh and it
is conditioned on the on the fact that
he needs to spend something like $30
million in 30 days without telling
anyone why and he can't acrue assets. So
he can't go and just buy cars. He needs
to throw parties and give money away and
and and spend money wildly. And it's uh
it's to teach him that money does not
bring happiness, of course. And I think
that's the solution to this. Uh anyway,
let me tell you about MongoDB. What's
the only thing faster than the AI
market? Your business on MongoDB. Don't
just build AI. Own the data platform
that powers it.
>> Here's why I'm not worried.
>> Why are you not worried?
>> Because I think that these ultra
talented, hardworking engineers. Yep.
>> Having some liquidity. Let's say
someone's been there for some number of
years. Yep.
>> They have 5 million liquid. They buy a
nice house somewhere.
>> Yep. and then realize, hey, I've got a
nice nest egg. Yeah, I can keep working
on crazy moonshot. I don't have to go
join, you know, the the the, you know,
historical example would be like work on
the hard thing or work on enterprise
SAS.
>> And I think this just will give people
um more confidence to work on the hard
thing. the thing that might have a 5%
chance of success, but if it's
successful,
>> you know, hasn't a tremendous impact on
on uh on on our country and things like
that. So,
>> it might happen for some people, but in
general, I I I do think that uh there is
this liquidity wave coming. Delian
talked about on the show yesterday. Uh
at the same time like SpaceX has been
doing tenders for over a decade and it's
not like the early employees have never
had a crumb of liquidity or secondary
throughout their journey. A lot of them
have had opportunities to sell at least
a portion of their stake and had been
able to buy houses. And there's always
been a way to access some of that
capital whether through a loan from a
bank and you're obviously more creditw
worthy if you own a bunch of SpaceX
stock and it's going up. Um, and uh,
>> yeah, bigger a bigger issue for the kind
of space economy overall is just the
Blue Origin people who like wasn't
didn't they have like way more?
>> Like they didn't they they didn't really
know what their equity was worth. They
didn't it's not like there was regular
tenders and so why work at the number
two at least by many definition space
company
>> and then that's potentially ultimately
bad for competition and it's bad for
>> la you know launch pricing for all these
other
>> companies that are reliant on the
SpaceX's and ultimately the Blue Origin.
So,
>> anyways, uh
>> crazy news out of China.
>> Mhm.
>> Apparently, the co-founders of Manis
uh are still in China and were called
up, uh to uh talk with the government
and are now blocked.
>> Have you seen The Dark Knight?
>> Yes.
>> Has everyone seen The Dark Knight? You
You thinking what I'm thinking? You
thinking what I'm thinking? We go there,
wrap our arms around him, the plane
comes, grabs the balloon, sucks him out
of the back of the of the skyscraper.
It's one of the greatest scenes, and I
think that's what we got to do cuz we
need personal super intelligence.
>> This was surprising to me because I feel
like we've been messaged to for a long
time that they were in Singapore.
>> Yes, that's true.
>> We shouldn't have been seeing this. It's
not a Chinese company. They're in
Singapore. The whole team's in
Singapore.
>> And and you would
It it takes some audacity to sell your
leading Chinese, one of the leading
Chinese AI companies during an AI a
global AI race,
>> this battle between great powers and to
sell to a big American hyperscaler.
>> Yep.
>> Maybe get out of the country before you
do that because it's not at all s I mean
>> this doesn't when when the manis
acquisition happened
>> Yeah. seem very clear that you would be
if you were China and you were competing
in the AI race. Yeah. Even though Manis
is not like a lab, you're still like,
>> okay, they're building a powerful
harness.
>> Yeah.
>> We probably don't want them going to
serve
>> and the harnesses are incredibly
probably under
>> more important now. Yeah. Super
important right now. Everyone everyone,
you know, obsesses over the models and
the models are important, but the the
harnesses have shown incredible promise
for actual diffusion and making these
models. So Josh Wolf says, "I thought
this wasn't a Chinese company." And uh
Delian goes for the jugular and says,
"So much for all the arguments about
Manis not being influenced by the CCPA,
>> Bill."
>> Yeah, I I'm I'm mostly shocked just
about how this is playing out. You You
would think that if you're the CEO of
Manis and you get a call from Mark
Zuckerberg and it even smells like a
potential acquisition, you're like,
"Yeah, I'd love to come see the
headquarters. Why don't I come and with
my team, we'll just come and hang out in
Menllo Park or Miami for a couple months
while we hash out the deal? And if the
deal doesn't go through, we'll head
back. But if it does, we'll just stay
and we won't go back because if it goes
through, then there's going to be
pressure and we're going to wind up in
this situation. This feels almost
predictable. I don't I don't know. It
feels like there's something else going
on here. I'm excited for this uh this uh
story to develop.
>> Authorities are reviewing the sale.
>> Yeah. and they're being asked not to
leave. Seems hard to reverse at this
point. But again, not sure why. I mean,
when you look back at
>> acquisitions that were blocked
historically, who knows?
>> Yeah.
>> Who knows how feasible it is to fully
block the acquisition, but they can
certainly block these individuals from,
>> you know, materially benefiting from it
in some way or contributing to Meta's
efforts. Well, here's some advice for
the CEO of Manis. When you get here to
America, when you get that liquidity,
that payday from Mark Zuckerberg, open
an account on public.com. Investing for
those that take it seriously, stocks,
options, bonds, crypto, treasuries, and
more with great customer service. Just
do it. And then, you know, tell your
story. Start rereaming one live stream,
30 plus destinations. You should be you
should be multireaming. So, go to
reream.com. Tell your story live on the
internet. Gabriel says,
uh, Meekmill has been going off. Yes.
About AI. AI is helping him organize his
whole music career and other businesses
in days and it's moving his business
forward at a high rate. Some tech Young
Bull I met on LinkedIn gave me an
incredible template which probably
GStack.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Um, who else can help me with Claude?
Uh, Gabe says, "Drake, I don't do K2
Kimmy DeepSeek. That's more for your
kind. My gal more like Demis theme park
ting London deep mine. Meek Mill I cla
coded perks out of 18th and Burks. I got
500 agent lawyers trying to free Lil
Dirk.
>> That's a good line. Bars.
>> Drake singing. You got me loco trying to
be your shoulder.
>> You didn't sing it.
>> Sophie chimes in.
>> Actually sing it.
>> Two chains. Open claw on my laptop
trapping off these Mac minis. Shout out
to YC. Real G's want to stack with me.
>> That's good. That is good. I mean, yeah,
it's not a it's not a bubble until until
GStack makes it into makes it into a
>> actual hit. The funny thing here is
there's some debate and and there's this
general vibe like some people were
latching on to this Trunk fan post about
like you know are people making fun of
me Meek Mill? Do are people like
underounting his ability to actually
build something for real? And the
interesting thing is that I would
definitely bet on Meek Mill to build a
real valuable piece of software for his
audience or his life or his business
over over any of these tech people
writing rap lyrics even with all the
powerful LLMs. Like the tools to
actually build software are way better
than the tools to write rap lyrics. And
and and it's interesting because you are
seeing this dynamic where where the like
like it I think a lot of people are
latching on to the older paradigm of
like oh like you know Jeremy Rener built
an Instagram clone at one point and it
was just the Jeremy Rener app and it was
just his feed of his photos and people
were like why does this exist? You can
just follow Jeremy Rener on Instagram.
It doesn't make sense that he would have
like his own private Instagram. Um and
he probably spent a lot of money
developing that piece of software. Uh
but and and I don't think it wound up
working and it didn't scale and he wound
up winding that project down. But uh if
you think about like well what if this
what if this cost of doing that is a h
100red bucks or 200 bucks or a thousand
bucks like all of a sudden the the
hurdle rate to clear something like that
actually does open up the creative
aspects where I I wouldn't be surprised
if there's a like maybe not like a
breakout hypers scale incredible like
generational company but just like in
terms of like you like you can be a
great musical artist and also produce
great clothing like you will now be able
to produce software at the equivalent
level like it is available and so if you
are constrained by your ideas and if
you're a creative artist you and you
have a great idea you're no longer going
to be in this world where you're like
well I need to put a couple million
bucks down for a software engineering
team and they're going to not really
take me seriously and all of a sudden
you get into this weird thing where like
the the app that they launch is like
sort of iffy and not that good. So, I
don't know. I'm actually I'm actually
coming away bullish on uh what Meek Mill
winds up producing over the next few
years.
>> And we are working on getting Meek on
the show.
>> I really hope we can talk to him.
>> I'll cover you. You're good. You're
good.
>> I'll cover Meta. Do you want to jump for
a second?
>> First, let me tell you about Crowd
Strike. Your business is AI. Their
business is securing it. Crowd Strike
secures AI and stops breaches. And I'm
also gonna tell you about Vanta,
automate compliance and security. Vanta
is the leading AI trust management
platform. and I'm totally good. So, I
can take uh the next intro.
>> I have a personal thing I'm going to run
to, but I will see you guys tomorrow.
Yes. Love you. Cheers.
>> Thanks, Jordy. Uh up next, we have Mike
from Ark Prize in the Reream rating
room. Let's bring him in to the TDP
Ultra Dome. I'm very excited to talk to
Mike. How are you doing?
>> Here we go. Hey. Hey. Good to see you
again.
>> Good to see you. Uh
>> I'm so excited. This is always the
highlight of the show. I love talking to
you about everything but uh what are we
talking about today? Uh reintroduce
uh ARC as an organization and then take
us through the actual do you even call
them benchmarks challenges what's the
right term?
>> I think benchmarks is a fair word.
>> Okay.
>> Um yeah couple almost three years ago
now co-ounded the arc prize foundation
me and France.
>> Um the archives foundation has a mission
uh to be the northstar of AGI. So uh
sort of our sort of job we have two of
them. One is to help be a useful sense
public sense finding tool for the public
to understand how close how far are we
towards AGI or not. Yeah.
>> Um and the second is to inspire progress
towards AGI. Um ARC is a a series of
benchmarks that um help highlight what
are some of the large remaining gaps
between what's frontier AI is capable of
and what humans are capable of. And we
sort of uh uh target that gap. That is
sort of uh our definition of ultimately
AGI is you know we we produce an ongoing
series of benchmarks um continually
studying frontier progress and uh you
know at some point we are not going to
be able to do that job anymore. We will
run out of ideas you know we'll test
frontier and say we can't find anything
else any more gaps and I think that'll
sort of be the moment when uh I think it
becomes commonly accepted to say okay
yeah we we've got AGI now and today we
are announcing and launching uh the the
newest best version of ARC arc AGI uh 3.
It's the latest in the series. This is a
really large uh format change from the
first two. Uh ARK 3 is designed to test
agentic int intelligence and it is as I
as far as I am aware and I've been sort
of interviewing folks all over the AI
scene in the last few weeks the only
unsaturated general AI agent benchmark
in the world. Um the headline score is
human score 100% and AI less than less
than 1%.
>> Okay. uh unpack that like launch because
I my conception of Arc AGI V3 is it's
almost like a 2D game. It's no longer
the puzzles where I'm picking colors to
match a pattern. It's actual uh moving
arrows on the keyboard. I'm stepping on
triggers. I'm opening doors, switches,
that type of thing. And um I played it
with you on the stream uh months ago.
>> Yeah. uh helped us launch our preview
several months back.
>> Okay. So, that was the preview.
>> Today, we got the fin the full data set
launching today.
>> So, so does that mean more I I'm going
to call them games more more actual
levels launching or is this that uh what
you're launching is like you did the
actual benchmark and got the four
leading labs to devote the compute and
actually open up their models to be able
to interface with the system to get the
scores.
>> Uh both things actually. So today um on
the benchmark side uh the public version
of the benchmark is uh or I guess the
the overall benchmark. So over 100 games
um nearly a thousand different levels
across these game-like environments. I
think it's fair to call them games.
We've designed them to be fun and games
are fun. Um I think you could look at
them you know from a research standpoint
more more as environments though. These
environments are intended to test
whether AI can effectively explore,
discover its own goals, acquire
strategy, develop plans, execute its
plans.
>> One of the really unique things about
ARK 3 compared to the one and two format
is that it is interactive now. Whereas
you mentioned, you know, one and two
look like these kind of static IQ
puzzles that were on a page.
>> Uh three challenges both humans and AI
to essentially figure out the uh figure
out the goals of themsel. um when you're
dropped into one of these environments,
your only goal explicitly is to win. And
so in order to figure out how to do
that, you have to actually, you know,
dedicate some uh some extra regulation
to figuring out the rules, the
mechanics, the strategy. And um one
important thing is you're sort of
playing these environments. This the
strategy mechanic, they grow and they
evolve and they change over time. And
this is one of the reasons I think AR3
will be a really useful tool for
understanding agentic intelligence this
year. I think it'll be our first real
test um or you know seeing early
progress on these AI systems that are
able to do on the-fly world modeling
some degree of on the like on the
continual learning. These are both like
critical capabilities um that we view as
missing today that Arc 3 tests for.
>> Okay. Uh
take me a little bit deeper on you you
said there's a thousand games or a
thousand levels.
>> A I think it's a a few overundred games.
Okay. Uh across those 100 environments
nearly a thousand levels. across all of
them.
>> Um, yeah, it's a much larger uh version
of uh of the of the benchmark than than
we've ever had previously. And then like
I mentioned before, the other major
thing we're announcing today is Frontier
scores. Okay, so the benchmark is is
launching. We're also publishing as of
today um the the the latest four models
uh across all the four major labs. And
yeah, I think Soda is currently sitting
at like 3% uh point4%
>> Gemini 3.1 Pro. Uh maybe there's an
extra hyphen it on there, but uh
basically the Gemini uh Anthropic and
OpenAI were all in the 0.2.3 something
and then uh Grock was I think it's 0% uh
walk me through uh the actual buildout
of these hundred games. Is this entirely
human done? Is there some sort of uh
computer aided tooling to insert
variation programmatically or is it
important that they're all created by
hand? How do you think about the
creation of
>> I I wish we could use uh AI to help
design games. We'd be able to make the
benchmark even big like better. Uh the
reality is um like humans are still the
bottleneck on creativity and so every
game has still been handcrafted and
handdesigned by humans. You could sort
of imagine if you were embedding all
these different levels on a big
manifold, you know, in an embedding, you
want them all as far apart as possible
in that sort of space.
>> And today, still humans are kind of the
limiting factor in terms of ensuring
that, you know, every game is is
different and as novel from from from
each other as possible.
>> Yeah.
>> Um there's a one there's a few
interesting uh design changes actually
from a benchmark standpoint compared to
to one and two. Maybe the the largest um
is you know, ARC studies the frontier
progress. we have to design our future
versions of benchmark uh to to adapt to
to changing Frontier progress. Um one of
the design goals with one and two was we
have what's called a private and a and a
public test split where we have a public
version of the benchmark and a private
hold out version which is what we
actually use to verify the performance
of Frontier models.
>> So so so the the Frontier models get no
freebies. They don't get anything from
the public set but they can try.
>> You can't memorize the public set,
right?
>> Or or or or they can they can experiment
on the front on the public set from like
a prompting perspective maybe.
>> Yeah. The idea is the public set is
intended to demonstrate the format.
Okay.
>> Um and this was similar with ARK1 and
two. However, we held a design goal that
the public sets and the private sets uh
were were called um ID with each other.
Basically that they um are are supposed
to be as close as possible to each
other. Um and it's just uh split along
visibility. Some are private and some
are public.
>> Sure. with uh one of the the big
advancements with AI reasoning is this
actually like not a very useful way to
run benchmarks. Uh AI reasoning systems
are so powerful now that they can
actually generalize across ID test
splits and this is what we saw with ARK1
and two. So with three, one of the big
design decisions is um we're actually
releasing fewer games into the public
demonstration set. So there's only I
think about 25 games that are in the
public set. We're actually explicitly
not even calling it a training set
anymore. We're calling it a
demonstration set just to show the
format to humans, you know, be able to
test your systems to make sure you can
sort of create them, get a feel for
them. There's obviously fun marketing
value in being able to play the games as
humans, too, which we really love. Uh,
and on the private set, this is the set
that's over 100 100 games. Um, they're
specifically different. They're they're
different. We designed them with
different characteristics, uh, different
goals, different um, uh, intelligence
capabilities required to beat them. The
difficulty, uh, the acceptance criteria
is more extreme between human and AI
performance. all to hopefully produce
the most useful like uh high signal uh
benchmark towards whether we actually
are getting real progress towards AGI
with the foundation models.
>> So uh
let me pitch you a strategy. If I have
access and I I you know I'm at I'm at
Google or OpenAI or Enthropic and I I
want to do well here. Can I take the
public set and uh create a log of all
the steps and all the all the reasoning
chains and all the key strokes that are
required to pass those levels and then
sort of like dump that into the context
window before I go off into the unknown
>> um and train your model that way.
basically
>> maybe train my model, but also I'm I'm
just wondering if if that's helpful for
for uh setting up the context or or or
like doing some sort of like pre
compaction of the strategies that are
learned. Maybe not even training a
custom model because I feel like that
would maybe be like bench hacking. I'm
more thinking about just like uh okay we
we went and we played all the public
games uh to completion and we and we
monitored them screen recorded them
tried to extract as many learnings as
possible into you know an MD file
basically and then we and then we
include that in the prompt that that
that kicks us off that to sort of
bootstrap the learning once we get into
the unknown environment. If we've done a
good job on the benchmark, you should
not be able to train a system on the
public set and perform well on the
private set. Um, if we've done a good
job, obviously every benchmark release,
it's an it it's an experiment. Yeah.
Right. We make contact with reality. We
ship these systems benchmarks publicly.
We we try to analyze the performance,
understand what they're good at and bad
at and evolve, you know, future versions
of the benchmark. But intentionally, you
know, and this actually is a um very
closely related to another design
decision that we're making with our uh
scoring function going forward this
year. And this is again in response to
like AI progress that we've seen. You
know, our our scoring methodology is
basically AGI field at this point. Um we
uh going forward with V3 are using as I
I kind of have um uh this idea of like
um uh basically a philosophy of having
uh essentially no harness.
>> Um we want to create a testing
experience that's as similar as possible
between the human and the AI test
takers. And when we have our human
baseline, when we have a, you know,
rented literally a testing center in San
Francisco, had, you know, hundreds of
humans play these games. Yeah. Um, all
they're given is uh you have sort of,
you know, sensory input through your
eyes and action motor output through
your hands back into our testing
interface. And all of the intelligence
happens between those two steps. And so
we try to emulate that as close as
possible for our verification function
where we have this sort of philosophy of
having a very stateless client. So that
our scoring function basically tries not
to introduce any kind of bias, any kind
of help, any kind of maybe potential
cheating strategy. If you go read our
prompt, it's extremely simple. It's
like, you know, you are playing a game,
here's your actions, your your
conversation will be carried forward to
the next turn, and that's it. Um, in
order to again kind of produce this
really clear signal towards when the
there's real progress towards AI and the
base intelligence layer, we're able to
detect that.
>> Okay. So take me back through history a
little bit because I'm surprised by why
AI is struggling with this in particular
because I remember it feels like almost
a decade ago that OpenAI had a product I
think it was called Jim where they were
able to beat Mario and then they beat
the Dota team Dota 5 and they were able
to do things that I can't do. I I
certainly can't beat Lisa Doll in Go. I
certainly can't uh you know win Jeopardy
or any of these things. And yet AI
systems were able to dominate those
games. You've created new games. What's
different about the games or the
strategies by the AI labs where we're
not matching up like we did in the past.
>> I think the biggest thing is the
expectation of what constitutes real
progress towards hi, right? when labs
were using games in maybe the 2016 to
2018 2019 era when they're very popular
um you know human researchers are
studying the games trying to understand
the failure modes of machine learning
deep learning trying to build custom
search like harnesses to uh and sort of
feedback mechanisms from the
environments it's very very handcrafted
it's loaded with what I'll call like
human G right in the research process
>> we are now at a point where we want to
control for that actually we want to
understand
>> like we we want to control for as little
human
in these like systems as possible,
right? We want to understand is can
basically AI do what the human
researchers were doing back in that era
in order to beat those games that they
had never been trained on or exposed to
before. Interesting. Um, so I do think
it's kind of elegant that you know we
are coming full circle where games are
these very minimal representations of
like actually important capabilities
that humans possess around exploring and
developing strategy and world modeling
and being able to learn on the fly. Um,
they're really they're really elegant as
far as an environment goes. Um, but I
think what's changed is our expectation
of how much human crafting is needed in
order to uh learn the games when they
haven't been specifically trained on
them is is is the big difference today,
especially with AR 3.
>> Okay. Uh, remind me of some more history
but more related to ARC. I remember with
one of the Arc AGI benchmark tests, uh,
there was a version from of a model from
OpenAI that was running on some sort of
like extra high mode and I seem to
remember like $2,000 per task being
cited something 03 big launch.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah, that was like a preview of 03 in
December of 2024. It's really the first,
>> you know, there's a great chart on the
Arc Prize homepage now where you can
actually see this data point so clearly.
Um I think one of the really you know
like I mentioned before one of our
missions of the foundation is to try and
be useful public sense finding tool.
>> Sure.
>> And um I think you know when we first
launched ARK one and uh two you know it
was a very common critique. It's
understandable you know hey these things
look like toys are they really
economically useful? Are they going to
lead to any you know real progress? Um
and now in hindsight I actually think
that's a pretty outdated view because we
have pretty strong evidence that ARC
held quite strong predictive power of
noticing really important hit moments.
We only started seeing uh saturation on
the V1 benchmark and remember V1 was
like 5 years old. We only started seeing
any amount of progress from LMS on V1
once we got AI reasoning which was a
really critical innovation I'd argue is
is as important as the original
transformer innovation. Um and then a
year later uh this was you know 4 months
ago now uh with the November December
2025 class of models with GPT 5.2 and
OPUS 4.5 we again started to see
saturation on ARCV v2 and it precisely
correlated with this like agentic coding
capability that that emerged. Yeah.
>> Um and so I'm hope I'm optimistic that
AR3 will again be a very useful sort of
predictive tool to understand when you
know basically AI agents are capable of
operating in more open-ended
environments. Yeah. Um right now you
know you need a lot of human
handcrafting to get these intelligence
systems to work in domains such as
coding right with cloud codec and code
codex and cloud code.
>> Um and that's we I I basically expect
that like when you are doing very good
on v3 uh which will mean by the way 100%
score v3 means like AI can sort of beat
all the games as efficiently as humans
can on an action basis that will lead to
economically useful systems where agents
are able to operate in more open
environments that they haven't been
citically trained on. Mhm. Uh I I I
still remember from RKGI one uh you know
you see these like 3x3 grids and the
first time I ever tried it I tried on my
phone and I think my phone was in some
weird like landscape mode or something
so it wasn't rendering correctly and I
was like
>> you didn't even get all the data points.
>> Yeah. No, so normally it's like you see
the blocks and then you see the blocks
to the left and the right and then I was
like wow I'm like I'm cooked like like
the fact that other people can do this.
Uh but of course once you load it on
desktop it's very usable. Uh I I want I
want to continue down that path of the
the the 03 extra high like what are you
seeing from the labs that put forth
models that did test on uh ARC AGI v3 in
terms of just steering the models
because we we we talk about GPT 5.4 but
that means a lot of different things
these days. Was this in the max
reasoning? Should I compare this to what
I'm seeing in chatbt? I'm getting more
and more drop downs where I can go, oh,
I can go pro and then I can go extended
thinking mode.
>> Is it is it an offtheshelf model or are
they able to sort of come to you and
say, hey, we want to we want to actually
marshall 10 times the amount of compute
for this particular challenge.
>> On our verification leaderboard, we have
a new testing policy. It's actually
something we did have with one and two
introduced after 03 where we limit to
$10,000 per verification run.
>> Okay. Um this is somewhat of a practical
like consideration. Yeah. Uh if we
actually used like the most expensive
highest you know million context window
of the most expensive model I think
testing of the full V3 private data set
would be like $100,000 which is just
kind of like silly right so we set a we
set a reasonable limit like humans near
nowhere near as much as sort of like
dollars to sort of produce this same
performance. I like that too because
like that is the that is the like like
getting AGI and it's like yes it can do
anything but it costs $50 million per
prompt to do one hour of human labor
like that's not really economically
valuable and so bounding
>> I think you want to know progress right
and I think $10,000 is a reasonable
amount of money where you will actually
see some degree of progress and that
will be a useful signal to start paying
attention to it more.
>> Yeah. Um it's and it's like just you
know for practical reasons we just can't
we're we're a strap nonprofit so you
know we have to be sort of thoughtful on
our on our sort of money on how we
deploy things.
>> Yeah that that's that's where so I think
the high reasoning mode is the most we
used on uh for the official verification
stuff that we've used today that I mean
do you spend a lot of time thinking
about your own AGI timelines? Has your
work at ARC shifted your timelines at
all or do you feel like I've always been
a 2035 guy I'm still a 2035 guy?
Something like that. like do you do you
have an internal model of this or is
that even useful these days?
>> I instead of um listening to my
predictions uh you should probably
follow our actions as our like best sign
of a sort of review of of progress. I
think the reality is we have made
tremendous progress with our reasoning
over the last 12 months.
>> Yeah.
>> Um ARC is uh operating to bring the next
version of the benchmark. We we've
already started work on v4. We actually
have plans written down already for V5
as well. Our intention is to bring these
to market annually over the next two
years. Um and so that that's sort of our
expectation of having the next version
ready right now.
>> Yeah.
>> Um now like will we actually launch
them? I think we'll have to just see
where Frontier Progress is. We want to
we want the future benchmarks to be as
useful as possible. And so if there's
like still a lot of utility and
scientific value in the current version
of the benchmarks, you know, we want to
keep focus on those. But to the extent
that like the scientific value is
starting to wayne, we want to have the
next version ready that has sort of like
identified, hey, are there other
interesting remaining large gaps between
what humans can do and AI can do in
order to drive that gap to zero. You
know, again, we're a very we're a very
AGI pill organization. We want to see
progress. We actually love seeing
progress. And part of our goal is to
inspire as much progress as quickly as
we can to to get to these AGI systems.
Yeah.
>> Um so I'd say like uh yeah, that that's
sort of the operating view. Um will, you
know, a common question would be like
well is V5, you know, is V3 AGI? V4 AI
D5 AGI no the honest answer and this is
something I've actually learned I had a
different view of this maybe three years
ago the honest answer is no single
version of any benchmark is ever going
to be a GI I think it is a uh the
frontier of progress is a moving target
and our job is to like understand that
the gap the remaining gap and and the
definition of that gap is going to
change as time goes forward in order to
keep chunking up what are the largest
pieces of that gap that we can find that
are interesting you know that identify
some missing important capability that
humans are able do um and produce
benchmarks that that showcase that gap.
>> Last question, I'll let you go. Uh
what's going on with the Pokemon bench
that feels somewhat related uh similar
tasks? What are you learning from that?
Uh how are models becoming so good at
that? It it feels like they aren't
specifically RL on Pokemon and yet
they're learning, but also there's a
massive amount of, you know, written
text about what to do at every level in
Pokemon. Are they just learning that
from the pre-training corpus? What what
what's your thesis on Pokemon?
>> It it certainly seems helpful. Um if I
use our experience in developing ARC as
a tool to sense finder on this, um we
have seen more understanding from the
latest generation of uh AI reasoning
systems over the last three months than
we saw in the first six months when we
were developing ARC v3. Um I think you
can kind of fork uh you can almost split
the research problem of agents into two
things. You can split it into a problem
that says can an AI agent effectively
perceive some kind of environment state
apply a strategy that's written down to
produce actions and you know
successfully execute a plan. That's half
the equation. The other half the
equation is can you have agents that are
effectively able to develop what that
plan is. And to do that, you need to be
able to on the fly build like a world
model of your your task, acquire goals,
create your strategy, create your plan.
We've seen a lot more progress on the uh
perception through strategy to action
problem than we've seen on the um the
exploration problem, the strategy
generation problem. And I actually think
this is one of the areas that that I
would point interested Arc 3 researchers
at because I think it's a lot more green
field um and will unlock a lot more
progress even on you know things like
Pokemon bench uh where it's kind of
coming down to like okay we know they
can sort of I should say at execution um
the exploration and planning step is
still where there's a a large degree of
bottlenecking still still happening
today.
>> Well congratulations on the progress. Uh
where can people find it? How can people
participate? How can people help out?
>> Yeah. Uh, go to arcprize.org. Uh, you
can play the games as humans. Like I
said, we've got almost 25 of them, I
think, on the site that they're all
they're all designed to be very fun. We
explicitly controlled for this actually
when we were doing human baseline
testing. So, that actually should be
fun. You can have fun. And you can also
get details there. Enter ARP prize 2026,
our new $2 million uh prize uh pool uh
this year that's on AR 2 and AR 3.
>> That's amazing. Yeah, our uh our our
teammate Tyler Cosgrove was climbing the
human leaderboard for a while. I imagine
he's been knocked off, but we'll have to
get him back on top. Uh, thank you so
much for taking the time to come chat
with me. Uh, this was fantastic. We'll
talk to you soon.
>> Have a good one.
>> Let me tell you about Gusto, the unified
platform for payroll benefits and HR
built to evolve with modern small and
mediumsiz businesses. And let me also
tell you about Turbo Puffer, serverless
vector and full tech search built from
first principles and object storage.
Fast, 10x cheaper, and extremely
scalable. And without further ado, we
have our next guest, Nathan from Airirst
Street Capital coming in to the TV.
Nathan, how you doing?
>> Great. How are you doing, John?
>> Thank you so much for staying up late.
Uh, what time is it there?
>> 7:25.
>> Okay. Not too bad, but past the workday.
Uh, uh, reintroduce yourself. It is your
second time on the show, but reintroduce
yourself and give us the news.
>> Yeah. Uh, I'm Nathan. I, uh, started a
venture capital firm called Air Street
Capital in 2019 to invest in AI first
companies. And, uh,
>> what year were you investing in AI?
Well, so I started the firm in 2019, but
started investing in AI in 2013, which
is probably around the time that like
deep learning was still definitely
cooking only in the lab and most people
didn't really care too much outside of
it.
>> Yeah. What were the median deal like?
What was the median deal like in 2013?
Was that like uh recommener systems?
Like we're going to bring Netflix
recommendations to everyone like that
type of thing?
>> Yeah. Well, it was uh e-commerce
recommendation systems, adtech.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh big data was the buzzword back then.
>> Sure.
>> A little bit in finance. Yeah. Like
insurance underwriting, like loan
prediction, credit
detection, that stuff.
>> Yeah. Fraud detection. Just like a big
uh I guess it was like a Were they doing
deep learning yet or was it mostly just
like
>> Yeah, they were. Yeah. I mean it was
2013 was the year that uh computers
started to be able to recognize images
better than uh than humans.
>> Oh yeah.
>> That was uh you remember like Andre
Carpathy was the infamous human
benchmark on imageet in 2013 PhD.
>> That's right.
>> So that was the year when uh when
basically like Alex uh uh at uh
University of Toronto like built AlexNet
which
>> was the first deep learning system
running on Nvidia card.
>> Yeah. Yeah. What what a remarkable time.
So, uh, what has it has it been easy? I
mean, you just raised a new fund. Has it
been easier to pitch this to LPs? What
have been the challenges and, uh, and
opportunities over the last few years?
>> Yeah, I mean, it's been a it's been a
sea change like in, uh, 2018, you know,
when I started, um, for Air Street, it
was like I'm, you know, by myself. So,
solo GP, super contrarian,
>> starting in Europe where risk aversion
is extremely high. uh trying to focus on
AI, which most people didn't really care
too much about, and then first-time fun.
Those are sort of like all the worst
like buying selection criteria that one
would have. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and then yeah, like I think, you
know, this this is very much like a
long-term journey like you know, I set
out with I'm going to do these early
stage investments, be high conviction,
invest in biotech, defense, vertical
software, dev infra uh you know, I stuck
with what I said. So you know investing
in like Cynthia 11, Black Forest and and
others.
>> Had like six exits to like Recursion and
uh you know a company that went public
and Amazon etc.
>> Yeah.
>> And then um and then yeah like first
fund was like $27 million. Fund two was
121 about 3 years later again pre-Chat
GPT.
>> Um and then uh and then this one's 232
million which at this point makes us the
largest solo GP in Europe.
>> That's amazing. So, us. You said solo
GP, but you said us. Who else is on the
team?
>> I'm you know what, like I'm kind of
guilty with the royal we thing. Um,
>> but uh but I I have uh two colleagues
who run talent and operations and then a
pretty sizable back office for like
admin.
>> Sure.
>> But everything that comes along with
like you know building brand, planning
founders, investing, fundraising, that's
all me and the decisions are just me.
>> And then also the the is it annual
report state of AI? I mean it's uh Yeah,
>> it's sort of a huge project. Do you
bring in collaborators on that?
>> Yeah, that started in 2018 to basically
create like a kind of canonical open
access document covering research,
industry, politics, and talent.
>> Yeah,
>> there are a number of contributors every
year who are sort of like at the coal
phase doing their PhD or like
transitioning between roles in AI labs
who help us kind of stay smart on things
and and also folks who've been working
on policy because it's become
increasingly important as we see in the
news almost every day. Yeah.
>> Um, and then the cool thing is like I
get contributions from companies and
labs and researchers every year and like
I think this last year when we last
talked there was like 50 people in the
Google doc kind of like leaving comments
being like hey I I tried this
implementation this paper like I had
this problem and then some other
person's like that was my paper this is
what I tried.
>> And it's like cool like community
document basically where we can kind of
get to the center of truth.
>> Uh
not to call you like lucky on timing. Uh
it's very fortunate that you have the
size of fund that you do for where we
are in the market cycle, but uh how hard
would it be to do what you're doing
today with a $27 million fund because it
feels like a 20 $27 million is like a
seed round for like a you know startup
with just an idea. Sometimes that's like
one one% of the of the seed round. Uh
but like is it can you even make plays
with that size fund if that's what you
were constrained to today?
I I think you have to decide like what I
did which is either you want to be like
a main player and lead rounds and
express your conviction and be early
etc. or you play the like large
portfolio model and then you have checks
and a lot of opportunities and for me
that job is like much more of like a
network SDR style job and less of like I
can make my own opinions like do the
research be there early and then when I
like something like really make the bet.
Yeah,
>> I don't think you can do the former like
be a lead investor in 27 million. No
chance. I think you can do the larger
portfolio um you know chipping into a
variety of rounds and still have like
good performance,
>> but it's just a different job that I
don't particularly enjoy um and doesn't
maximalize like my strengths and my
interests as much.
>> Yeah.
>> Um you know, so I I think at the end of
the day like you got to pick what what
flavor is good for you and then try as
best as you can to bring the best
product to the market given your
circumstances. And you I was fortunate
with fund 3 to be able to really come
with like a blank slate with, you know,
long-term partners and say like this is
what I think is going to be the most
convincing model, you know, right up to
$15 million in first checks and do a
couple growth stage rounds up to 25
million. Wow.
>> But still, you know, high conviction 20
companies and and of course like I'm,
you know, mostly based in Europe, but
still invest in the US and spend decent
time there as well.
>> Yeah. I I mean I know you're you're
you're in Europe but you're not you know
an exclusive European investor by any
means but uh I am interested in the
thought exercise of like where is the AI
opportunity uh internationally
um if I were to just back of the
envelope it I'm I'm you know I've seen
some of the sovereign AI efforts it it
sort of makes sense that like a certain
government might want to buy from a
particular uh local lab but at the same
time like you know Google has been very
successful internationally and you know
China got the the the Google of China
but many other European countries didn't
get the local Google competitor or the
local Amazon competitor or the local
Microsoft or Apple competitor just
because like they were consumer products
and consumers kind of flow wherever they
want. Um but at the same time I can
imagine if Google or OpenAI or Anthropic
is going to build a data center they
might want to go to a local Neocloud or
there might be opportunities for you
know the Harvey of some other country
that has different laws and different
rules and uh so how are you seeing the
shape of like opportunity outside of
America in AI?
I I think you covered it really well and
I would generally agree with you on this
uh you know Europe doesn't need its own
Google per se and in fact historically
like the government uh has tried there
was Quero and
>> uh one or two other initiatives that you
know had hundreds of millions of dollars
pumped into them so that they could like
capture European culture better than
Google could and
>> I think that's a bit bizarre when you're
talking about a learning machine. Yeah.
But um but so there's certainly some
sectors where I think like the
sovereignty like really matters and it's
not just marketing speak. So, you know,
defense and security is clearly one
where um you know, Europe woke up to
this like two years ago and and and now
even more so uh with the Middle Eastern
war that's ongoing.
>> Uh you know, as an example, like I
invested in a business called Delhi and
Alliance Industries doing defense
autonomous defense systems, right, in
Greece. And one of the number one things
we got from people outside of Greece,
particularly in the US, is like, why are
you investing or building a company in a
vacation resort that I go sailing in,
you know?
>> Yeah. And then that narrative changes
significantly once you start seeing
shahit like drones hit you know UK bases
in Cyprus and you realize like okay the
border to southern Europe actually comes
over the Mediterranean Greece. Um I
think the the other part uh which is
which is interesting is like ambitions
change and um and I think in Europe
where traditionally there's been fewer
role models that one can look to and say
I'm going to be like that person and I
know the path
>> um some companies grow and you know for
example I think Lora originally started
as Leia like started in Sweden right and
it was the idea of
>> hey we should do this locally in Sweden
and um and now like clearly that
company's ambitions are like no we can
go ahead headto-head with Harvey.
>> Yeah. Yeah. It does feel like in Europe
like the the entrepreneurs that break
out, they're not saying I'm building X
for Europe. It's like I'm building 11
Labs. I'm going to go everywhere. I'm
building Spotify and I'm going to go
everywhere. And yes, I happen to be from
some other country and I'm going to have
a headquarters there, but get ready New
York because we're going to have a
headquarters there and we're going to
have an engineering hub in SF and like
we're just going to be an international
company and have our roots there.
>> Uh and that seems great right path.
>> Yeah. So this is why I think if you're
going to invest in Europe, it's really
important to have this foothold and
knowledge of the US market so that you
can apply the same quality distribution
>> that you see in the US over in Europe.
And either there are people who start
from day one being that ambitious or
there's others that are that grow and
and kind of
>> uh yeah just like fuel their batteries
with ambition as they see and experience
it, you know, like when you get success,
you want more of it. And so that's like
the kind of recursive cycle that the
continent's going through.
>> Yeah. I mean with all the progress from
the big labs and they're at such
incredible scale now like how are you
processing the SAS apocalypse and just
advice for founders of like what gets
steamrolled versus what doesn't? I mean
there were some there was some founder
we've had a couple founders on the show
that have been like we're doing AI
generated video social network and then
it was like you're getting steamrolled
and then it was like actually like you
know Sora is not going to be in the app
store anymore so like maybe that was a
good bet. I don't know. I'm not on that
particular app but uh it feels harder
and harder. It used to be just like
don't do an app that's just a prompt
around the foundation model. Like that's
done. But now we're talking about oh is
there pressure on CRM? Is there pressure
on databases? Is there pressure like
what will the labs do? It's it's
unpredictable. But how are you working
through it?
>> I think you know one thing you could say
is like what are the problem sets and
areas that like the smartest AI people
want to work on and like don't do that.
>> Okay.
>> So like
>> that's a good one. like don't do coding
and then like after it seems like AI
researchers really like AI for science
so like don't do that either.
>> Totally. Totally.
>> Yeah. Yeah. We have a friend from the
show that does like uh Yeah. It's an AI
company but it's for like small
businesses like HVAC owners and helping
them. It's like yeah I don't think
that's on the road map.
>> That's really good. Um,
you know, jokes aside, I think I think
uh it comes down to like this tacid
knowledge and like where you can capture
how people do a task and taste. Like I
see this a bit with our job like
>> you know I'm using like I'm claing as
well and like codeex maxing. It's
amazing how it can how you can imbue it
with your taste and you're like at some
point you realize okay we've built like
a learning machine that basically is
like a civ. you can pour as much as you
want into it and it'll still like learn
stuff
>> where before it was only one task at a
time and like forget accumulating
multiple tasks. So at this point if
you're really AGI pill like you have a
call you pipe the feedback in you ask
like hey how did I do and you get
suggestions you do that on the next one
you pipe it back in and then you're like
make a skill file and then next time
>> like here's a new opportunity and like
dude if you're not doing that it's like
game over. Yeah. And so I really do
think especially for our job like there
is a point at which you're like you know
solo GP with like 200 or$300 million
with a bunch of AIS.
>> Yeah.
>> So like
>> I'll call you in 10 years and see if it
works.
>> I'm excited. I'm excited. Uh well I want
to hit the gong for the new fund raise.
Congratulations.
>> Thank you for coming on the show. Have a
fantastic rest of your day and I will
talk to you soon. Have a good one.
Goodbye. Let me tell you about vibe.co.
Co, where DDC brands, B2B startups and
AI companies advertise on streaming TV,
pick channels, target audiences, and
measure sales just like on Meta. And let
me also tell you about Plaid. Plaid
powers the apps you use to spend, save,
borrow, and invest, securely connecting
bank accounts to move money, fight
fraud, and improve lending now with AI.
And without further ado, our next guest
is in the reream waiting room. We have
Rohin Dar. He is uh a real estate
expert. Thank you so much for joining
the show. How are you doing, Rohan? Good
to meet you.
>> Good. Happy to be here. Uh since this is
your first time on the show, would you
mind kicking it off with an introduction
on yourself and I'd love to know uh some
of your background, how you got to where
you are today?
>> Yeah, I um I'm a San Francisco real
estate agent and I'm you know among the
top highest producers by volume in the
city and uh I came from a little bit of
a traditional background. I did a YC
startup. I went to Stanford business
school. I did a bunch of startups and
then
>> got into real estate when kind of
learning about Airbnb early on and built
a small portfolio of that and uh and
then learned the real estate craft from
that.
>> Did you have to get a license at some
point? Did you join a big firm or did
you just sort of strike that?
>> I mean I was my Twitter account started
growing cuz I was like posting
interesting houses that I was like
>> just kind of curious about and then
people were messaging me like, "Oh, I
actually like bought that house you
>> No way. uh posted about and so I was
like, "Dang, like someone's making a lot
of money off of this and it's not me."
So then I like decided to get licensed.
And originally I was going to focus on
like Airbnb markets and short-term
rentals and vacation areas, but I live
in San Francisco and I could see the
prices were like after the pandemic just
like crashing here
>> while they were shooting up everywhere
else in the country and I was like, "Oh,
they're converging and that's that's
like odd to me." And so I was like,
okay, well YC moved here. Open AAI is
just sort of like getting traction and
the city's getting better. I think
everyone was sort of agreeing to that.
And then I was like, well, this is the
opportunity and I'm getting licensed and
like this is what I'm going to focus on.
And then uh and then I had a lot of
traction with it. So I just sort of got
sucked in to be sort of a, you know,
full service like, you know, Rowan in
your corner real estate agent when
you're trying to buy or sell a place. So
>> I love it. Uh when did the actual
rebound start? where where was the
trough after co
>> um so the interesting thing about like
co was 2020 2021 everyone was leaving
San Francisco but the prices kept going
up because interest rates were like
practically zero and there were all
these liquidity events so prices were
>> rising even though things were looking
like a little bit desperate in the city
>> and then when interest rates rose that
sort of like tampered the liquidity in
the market and then sort of at very end
of 2022 things like abruptly dropped. So
2022, end of 2022, 2023, 2024 prices
were way down. Um, and then 2024 by the
end of it there was like a little
trickle and 2025 you sort of hit had
come out of the bottom, but it was like
a slow,
>> you know, like you know, pretty stable
market, but on the upward trajectory.
and then end of 2025 then it just sort
of started booming like crazy in terms
of pricing and then even from like you
know March 2026 is like way up compared
to like 2 months ago. So,
>> so yeah, what does it actually take to
raise a family if you're working at a
tech company in San Francisco? Because I
think a lot of people will move to
suburbs, but walk me through, you know,
if you're coaching someone that has a
couple kids, they want schools, they
want access to their employer, like how
should they be thinking about what it
takes to find a great place in San
Francisco these days?
>> Um, you know, I don't even know if
people think of it that way. I think
it's like
>> San Francisco is just like such a scarce
place in in all ways. Uh it's like
>> they there's not enough housing, there's
not enough like restaurants, there's not
enough this or that. And it's sort of
like
>> if you want a place like in San
Francisco, you're like so convicted on
the idea of it of the city of like the
tech industry, you're like, you know
what, I'm just going to like do this and
then I'll figure the rest of it out.
Mhm.
>> Um, and so like I don't think people are
like, "Oh, now I have to figure out like
what school my kids are going to go to
or like what my commute will be or this
or that." It's like if you sort of like
dillydally around the edges, you sort of
end up never really sort of being so
committed and that kind of ends up being
like what makes it hard to buy a place.
But like the people that like actually
win these uh homes, whether they're at
like, you know, any price point, it's
it's like there's something mentally
inside them that's like this is the
place for me. Mhm. And what does the the
the like the down the fairway place in
San Francisco look like these days? Is
everything over two million, three
million? Like where are we in terms of
single family?
>> Kind of trying to find a place that is
uh that would fit four people and might
have parking and a second bathroom and
two or three bedrooms.
um say like a year ago it was like
around 2 million and then if you were
slightly above that price there'd be
like a big drop off in competition.
>> Uh and now it's like that level is sort
of definitely moved up to like threeish
million.
>> Um but there the bigger change too is
that like there's like huge level of
competitions at any price point now.
>> Okay.
>> Um if it's like one that sort of checks
the box for buyers.
>> So give me some advice if I'm trying to
win one of those competitions. What do I
have to do? I have to show up with all
cash. just put the cash in the bag. What
do I do?
>> I mean, all c I mean, in any given offer
process, like there'll be a decent
number of allcash buyers. So, it's not
like it's going to you can walk in and
be like, "Oh, I'm going to
>> win this cuz I'm all cash." Like, assume
like a third or you know,
>> half might be over a certain price
point. Um, and like I think what you
sort of have to realize is there's going
to be a range of competition on any
given house. So, like some houses,
>> uh, you know, this could be like a five
or $6 million house, a pretty expensive
house, and there might be like 15
offers.
>> Whoa.
>> And like the seller's not like going to
just sell it to you cuz you're a cool
guy. Like they're they the market will
sort of dictate the price. And
unfortunately
>> for buyers, you just have to say, you
know, the highest price and the best
terms to win.
>> Okay.
>> Um, and so like what you're sort of
trying to navigate is the level of
competition any one house is going to
have. So like say it doesn't have as
many bathrooms as you want, but you
could figure out how to add one or say
it's like offmarket and only a few
people know about it, so there's less
competition. And so like
>> your lever of getting a good deal on a
house isn't like just like participating
in a massive auction. It's like trying
to participate in a in an auction only
you know about or a smaller sort of you
know a different kind of property. So,
>> and you're probably expecting it to go a
lot higher, I imagine, with IPOs. The
labs are getting bigger, there's more
liquidity, there's new investment rounds
happening. What's your forecast?
>> Um, well, obviously it's like uh, you
know, hard to ch, you know, predict the
future, but I wasn't like, oh, I want
I'm a San Francisco real estate agent,
you know, like I'm going to say like,
you know, whatever. or like I decided to
get into the market cuz I thought like
this was going to happen. I was like,
"Oh,
>> like these scarce homes are going to
become more valuable and people will
wish they bought them and like I should
focus on this." And so like personally
I'm convicted like
>> the city is on the right trajectory now.
Uh so it's not like contrarian to buy a
place here at the moment. Yeah.
>> Um and then there are like liquidity
rounds and like that has made a big
impact on the market and if the
liquidity rounds get bigger like there's
it's a fixed number of homes that the
you know that money goes into. So
>> what do you think uh expansion looks
like over the next few years? Are we
going to I know Mil Valley is booming.
There's other suburbs. Is Oakland going
to happen? There's this California
Forever development that's happening
that's further out. like uh are you
starting to broaden your horizons or do
you want to stay focused and what do you
think the real estate buyer will want to
do in the near future? So, I I solely
focus on San Francisco like buyers and
sellers. Um
>> cuz like I found that like
>> in order to like every time especially
on the buyer side to win, it's sort of
like p pulling off this like mission
impossible like heist uh where it's so
elaborate. You have to know like every
detail about the market. Um
>> and so for me personally like I feel
very strongly that I can really help
people in San Francisco. That makes
sense. But then if you put me in Mil
Valley, it's like, oh, I mean, I don't I
mean, maybe it's good for me to help
serve Mil Valley customers, but it's not
good for them. So,
>> I think like, you know, if you're going
to use a real estate agent, you should
use one that like really knows a
particular market really well. So, for
me, I want that to be San Francisco.
>> Yeah. How much of the San Francisco boom
is attributable to the labs being based
in San Francisco like specifically as
opposed to the previous generation of of
tech? uh boom times happening in Menllo
Park, Certino, sort of on the peninsula.
>> Yeah, I'd say it's about like 5050 like
explaining what's going on. Like on one
hand, like what's really driving it is
like the perception that the city is on
the right track with like the mayor and
like walking around and it just feels
better and it feels fun and people are
moving there and sort of like it sort of
regained the zeitgeist of like a place
you move to to invent the future. Mhm.
>> So, I think that's like half of it. And
then the other half of it is it like
yeah, like we've had very successful
companies in San Francisco, tech
companies, but we never had the big one
like Meta or Google or Apple. And now
like we have two, you know, that like
just started that are uh within that
range and like
>> um it's somewhat unprecedented I think
even though we've had like hundred
billion dollar companies before and like
massively successful
but this is at a different level an
order of magnitude and so that's just
going to drive up uh attention and
excitement and all sorts of things. Uh
what are the most underrated
neighborhoods? What's on the come up
right now?
Um, you know, everyone sort of really
wants like Noi Valley, Pack Heights,
like I think if like if you're sort of
like looking in the Noi area like
Bernal, like the the m kind of the hills
right next to it, Glenn Park,
>> like you know, Sunnyside is like
dramatically less expensive.
Um, like Pack Heights is now like
getting to be like back to its sort of
premier level pricing, but Russian Hill
is like right next to it and like a
little bit less like walkable and in
this, you know, but like, you know, just
as great, but now the prices are up
there. And then like Knob Hill is next
to that and the prices are still a
little bit down there. So maybe I'd say
Knob Hill and uh, you know, Bernal
Heights.
>> Well, uh, where can people get in touch
with you? How do people reach out if
they're looking to San Francisco?
>> You know, Google me, Rohandar, and then
find my email or just reach out to me on
Twitter and I'm pretty active there and
you know, generally I just share what's
going on in the market over there. So,
>> fantastic. Well, we appreciate you
taking the time to come chat. Thanks so
much.
>> Awesome. Yeah.
>> Have a great rest of your day. We'll
talk to you soon.
>> Thank you. You too.
>> Goodbye. Let me tell you about
Cognition. They're the makers of Devon,
the AI software engineer. Crush your
backlog with your personal AI
engineering team. And let me also tell
you about graphite code review for the
age of AI. Graphite helps teams on
GitHub ship higher quality software
faster. And without further ado, we have
Eric Jorgensson, good friend of mine. He
is the author, the publisher of the book
of Elon.
>> Thank you so much for sending these. It
looks fantastic. And I was particularly
I want to get into the the book, but I I
I think partnering up with Jack Butcher
on this deeply underrated. Uh he is uh
an incredibly special illustrator,
designer. I don't even know what you
call Jack Butcher, but obviously he was
helpful in this, but uh thank you so
much for taking the time to join the
show. How are you doing?
>> Thank you for having me. I'm I'm honored
to be here. Uh and extremely excited to
put this thing out into the world.
>> Yeah, listen to that voice. You got a
voice for live streaming. Let's go. The
microphone's helping. You got a good
setup. It's great.
>> Am I about to get discovered right now?
>> I think so. No, of course you've been
online a million times. We Everyone
knows you. But uh uh maybe maybe take me
back to uh a little bit of like how you
got into publishing, your business
overall, the the the Naval book, and
then we can go into the Elon book.
>> Yeah, that's an amazing setup because
then I get to shout out Jack Butcher
again. Um, basically like I was tweeting
and blogging happily uh in like 2017 and
I had been following Nal. I learned so
much from him over the years
>> and I felt like he was putting out this
timeless wisdom that was just dissolving
into the the stream every day and it
just broke my heart that it was going to
>> get lost, get buried so quickly.
>> Yeah. Yeah. This is the thing with
Twitter. It's it's it's ephemeral which
is amazing but there's no
rediscoverability. We actually put out
this account once, Banger Archive, where
we would just share screenshots of old
tweets and they would go viral again.
But Twitter doesn't X isn't set up to
resurface stuff like that like YouTube
is, like Netflix is, and so the back
catalog really goes stale, but you were
able to obviously repurpose it.
>> Yeah. I I think um so many of the great
books have this like long fat tale of
timeless wisdom that we keep needing to
revisit. and Naval was was um you know
obviously has done an incredible job
distilling that wisdom and articulating
it for sort of our era and I wanted to
preserve that in a permanent format and
that side project that I did on nights
and weekends um and published you know
hoping to sell a few thousand copies has
gone on to sell I think we're coming up
on two million I've given away 5 million
more digital versions and 40 languages
>> crazy such a huge number I feel like
it's hard to sell a thousand books and
you've sold 2 million.
>> That is a that is an unbelievable number
for those that don't have like inside
context in the book industry. Like I
think the median outcome is like a few
hundred and like 10,000 is top fraction
of a percent.
>> Yeah, absolutely incredible. Uh what was
the strategy? I mean Naval has a big
audience but I don't see him pumping
this book constantly on his Twitter feed
or his X feed. Like how did this book
actually get in the hands of customers?
Is it like top of Amazon? Is it on the
New York Times bestseller list? Like how
do you even sell that many books?
>> I cannot explain it other than to say it
has become like a word of mouth
phenomenon. I think it is just so many
people tell me they buy it as gifts or
they recommend it or they give it to you
know I know teachers they give it to
every class that comes through and it's
just sort of um it's un who doesn't the
subtitle of the book is
>> a guide to wealth and happiness like big
TAM right like universal human desires
and new people graduate into like trying
to figure that out for themselves
>> every day and uh I I think it is
>> you know this really rich dense
collection of
>> Naval who's a really really gifted sort
of uh distiller and articul some of the
most important principles that
>> make life make lives successful.
>> What what principles from that book
either stick out to you are timeless or
maybe even underrated uh that you keep
coming back to you?
>> I think uh I mean the on the wealth side
like leverage um is is still an
underrated one. I mean you guys are
living examples of this. Uh authenticity
is another one that like that word is
thrown around so much that it becomes
sort of a cliche. Uh but the people that
we tend to admire the most or that are
doing the best are a really interesting
combination of like excellent,
authentic, and leveraged, right? Like
Jack Butcher is an incredible example.
You don't even really know how to
describe him. He's like he's an artist,
but he's a contemporary artist in the
digital era and he's a really gifted
designer and he's kind of like inventing
this category of worked art, but
whatever he is is him and it's awesome
and it's massively leveraged and you
know, he's doing things that nobody else
is is doing in the art game.
>> Do you think that
being controversial is correlated with
authenticity?
Because if you're not authentic, you can
be this very polished one side, you
know, me manyfaced thing. You interact
with one person in a certain way,
another person in another way. You make
everyone happy. You're less
controversial. As soon as you start
wearing your heart on your sleeve, being
authentic, you're going to attract some
people that don't like what you're
showing them because you're showing them
the true self. Is there anything there?
>> Is a great question. I bet there's two
opposing archetypes. I bet there is a
type of person that is extremely
inauthentic in how they
>> court controversy for the benefit of,
you know, the algorithm or just being
elevated by being attacked. And I bet
there's another PE set of people that
>> are authentic despite
>> any headwinds uh or controversy that
might come up. And I think the only way
to probably tell the difference is just
zoom out and see who's been doing what
for how long and in under what context.
Mhm. So, uh,
how obvious was it that Elon was going
to be the next subject? I imagine that
the playbook that you ran, the process
that you ran with the Naval book could
apply to a lot of entrepreneurs. It's
very it's a very interesting style where
it's it it it's it's it's high leverage.
I I can only think I can only describe
as high leverage because you're you're
standing on the shoulders of giants
which is like all of the work that
they've produced all of the podcasts
that they've done everything that they
have written. There's a lot of primary
uh research there that doesn't
necessarily require the same you know
access and permission and you can do a
lot of pre-work
uh independent before you actually go
in. Whereas some other books it's like
okay this author didn't even get the
interview with the person that they're
writing about like they sort of you know
no one wanted this book to happen and
that's a lot harder right um so so so I
imagine that the list was pretty long
how did you narrow it down uh how did
you land on Elon why this person why
this time
>> yeah this is an interesting it's an
interesting type of book because as you
point out like I'm not writing about
someone I'm trying to get out of the way
it's not about my opinion of them my
northstar are with these books is to
just be as for the book to be as useful
as possible to the reader. I want the
reader on every single page to be like,
>> "Oh my god, this is a great use of time.
I got a highlight on every page. I'm
getting so much out of this. I feel like
I'm getting personally mentored by Elon
Musk through a few hours of reading
about his most valuable and timeless
ideas." Right?
>> And I think for those of us in tech,
Elon's been interesting for a very long
time. And over the last, you know, five,
six years, uh, he's become more
controversial. But inside tech, he was
before he was a household name, he was
the most ambitious person in tech. And
nobody knew how that story was going to
end, right? He was
running on a very thin tight rope for a
really long time with both Tesla and
SpaceX.
>> And more recently, people have started,
I mean, Mark Andre and Brian Armstrong
maybe most famously have started asking
the question like, how does Elon do it?
Like what is this? Why is he an outlier
among outliers? And I wanted to answer
that question. And I think this book
does that
in more ways than I anticipated at the
outset, right? Like I there was some
interesting stuff that everybody kind of
knew would come in and there's like the
greatest hits and then there's the back
catalog and then how it all comes
together is actually like what's really
interesting.
>> Yeah. I remember in college someone
called me and was like, "Oh, I heard
about this this entrepreneur named Elon
Musk and he runs two companies. SpaceX
and Tesla and I was like, "Of course I
know about that. I'd learned about it
like three months earlier." Um, but but
it really was a very uh a very
controversial thing to do. The you know
the the timeless wisdom is like focus
focus focus. How have you perceived
Elon's ability to be like the exception
that proves the rule versus a pattern
that might actually be more replicable
than people think if they just adopt a
particular stance in how they leverage
what they're capable of to build
multiple companies simultaneously.
>> Yeah, there's a couple there was a
period where Jack Dorsey was running two
companies period where Steve Jobs was
running two companies. Uh, and there's
plenty of companies that are collections
of
meaningfully different companies kind of
in one under one name. Um, I think it's
kind of hard to extricate like what does
run the company mean?
>> Yeah.
>> Really on a day-to-day basis. And who is
around and who's running different
functions like Elon running a company
probably looks a lot different than
Steve Jobs running a company or than,
you know, Bill Gates running a company
or Mark Benny off, right? the the
motions that he dives deeply into are
very different kind of on a per leader
basis.
>> Yeah.
>> And
there's an element of this that like NAL
points this out. I think it's super
interesting. He's like you are probably
working harder on your company than NAL
is or than Elon is working on any one of
his companies just because he has this
divided attention. So let's just say
he's working 80 hours a week but he's
only working 30 hours a week on SpaceX.
>> Yeah. like how is he able to have orders
of magnitude more impact uh in those 30
hours than you're having with your 70?
Well, it is sort of it is sort of
interesting like maybe ironic that uh
his main competitor over the last two
decades has been Jeff Bezos at Blue
Origin who's also running two companies
and so like retired and
>> yeah I mean now now maybe more focused
you know he's retired but there was a
long time like a full decade where Jeff
Bezos was running Amazon full-time and
then you know Blue Origin was the
halftime or side project and and Elon
sort of didn't have a direct like
full-time you
by the book entrepreneur just building a
direct competitor in that one space
fully focused. So I don't know maybe
maybe that's luck maybe maybe things
play out differently if if there was
someone in that space but it's clearly
it's clearly worked out. Um yeah,
>> we kind of end up conflating like Elon
the person. Yeah. Like Elon the core
team around him and Elon the the symbol
frankly. Um and especially at this point
in his
>> career. He's one of the most leveraged
people alive, right? So
>> we are ascribing to like quote unquote
Elon what is actually the effort of tens
of thousands of engineers and you know
on plenty of other employees and fans
and supporters. Um and there's there's
beauty to that, right? like we are
humans. We rally around people um kind
of better than we do with symbols. Um
but that becomes this rallying like this
uh this rallying point for people to
like organize around the values
exemplified by this person. And I think
that's uh that's beautiful and magical
and part of
>> the formula. Uh but it does tend to like
if you conflate the conversation about
the guy with the conversation about the
symbol, you end up in this really weird
>> Yeah. kind of arguments with people,
you're not even really talking about the
same thing.
>> How how do you think about the the
thinking in decades concept? You know,
it's something that everyone in Silicon
Valley says, "Oh, you got to think in
decades." And then Elon comes out with
something that's like 20, 30, 40 years
away. And everyone's like, "No, we
didn't actually want thinking in
decades. I want to know something that's
going to happen for sure in like five
years tops." Uh, and I'm thinking about
this mass driver uh question and I'm
wondering like now that you've you've
written this book, you've you've studied
Elon, like h is this a departure? Is he
thinking even farther in the future or
has he always been thinking around this
time horizon? Like how similar is this
crazy mass driver on the moon pitch
compared to previous eras?
I think it's difficult to predict as are
many things but the if his theory and
his acting principle is that the future
is arriving ever faster
>> right and so things that at our previous
growth rate or technology trajectory
seemed like they were 30 years away are
actually now maybe 10.
>> Uh and it's really difficult to adjust
for that like recursion factor.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah, that makes sense. Yeah. Um, well,
where can people find the book?
>> Uh, anywhere you buy books. Amazon,
Barnes &Oble.com. Yeah,
>> Target. Uh, it just came out like
yesterday.
>> Are you going to do an audio book?
>> Yeah, the audio book's out.
>> I didn't read it.
>> Oh, you got to read. You got this. We'll
be those pipes. Put them to work. Well,
uh, Eric Jorgensson, thank you for
joining. The the the book is The Book of
Elon. You can go find it everywhere.
Books are sold. And we will talk to you
soon, Eric. Thank you so much for to
join the show. Uh let me tell you about
Figma agents. Meet the canvas. Your AI
agents can now create and modify your
Figma files with design system context
in beta starting today. And our next
guests are live here with us in the TBP
Ultradome. Thank you so much for taking
the time to join us. How are you doing?
Please uh since this is your first time
in the show, introduce yourself for
everyone.
>> I am Jenny Jess, co-founder of Peak Six.
>> Yes. And I'm Matt Holizer. um Jenny's
husband and also co-founder.
>> Fantastic. Take us back in time. I want
to hear the founding story.
>> Founding story. Start.
>> Um
we both grew up on the option trading
floor, Chicago and New York.
>> And we were at an sort of an infamous
options trading firm called Okconor
Associates.
>> You were both at the same firm.
>> We were both at the same different
cities. Yeah. So super lucky to be
trained there. when they did their
merger acquisition UBS.
>> Who was in Chicago?
>> I was.
>> Did you ever go to Series?
>> Oh, of course. Series is amazing. Yeah.
Anyway, it's a bar.
>> Be kind of modern these days.
>> Oh, yeah. I worked at Citadel in college
and that was the place where we'd go and
hang out and they'd uh give you you'd
order like a like a a rum and coke and
it would just be a full glass. It was
crazy. That's right.
>> A really good greasy sandwich to go with
it. Yeah. Really good. Good fries.
>> Okay. So, you're in Chicago?
>> Yeah. So, we're in Chicago. Um we decide
we started working together.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
>> what were you trading at the time?
>> Equity options. Both of us were
>> Equity Options.
>> Yeah. And then when they did the
original Swiss Bank joint venture, we
were part of the team that went to start
the OTC.
>> Okay.
>> Derivative Desk. So there was just three
of us. Um there's a gentleman from
Goldman who came in. And so we're like,
"Oh, this is cool. We're in our mid20s
starting a business, you know, an
entrepreneur." And when things started
going really well and then UBS came in
and they were moving to the East Coast,
>> we're like, well, we're not moving. He
had actually just come from New York.
>> Yeah.
>> And my family's in the Midwest, so we're
like, we're just we'll just do that
thing again. Yeah.
>> So that thing was to partner with a
bank. That was our plan A.
>> And
>> do over over-the-c counter derivatives.
>> Okay. weeds 28 and a half years later.
We've still never done it,
>> but we did invest really early in tech
and education. And so we c we created a
proprietary options trading firm. Okay.
Which is
>> 28 and a half years old that has never
had a losing year. Wow.
>> And it allowed us to self-fund Yeah.
>> all the things we've done since then.
>> And what's the secret to such an
incredible run with no losing years? Is
that risk management? Is that the
particular uh strategy? Like how how
does that come together? because I can't
think of another investor who's ever
done that.
>> It's unusual for sure. But
>> it's a secret.
>> Well, I think it tends to be about like
our approach. Our approach was not to be
smarter with our our algorithms. It was
smarter with our business model. So,
there are plenty of businesses that
haven't had losing years in the last 29
years. tend to be technology firms
>> that are basically providing a service
into the market which is the approach
that we I mean we we
>> we talked about ourselves as uh
>> Wendy's or Walmart, Walgreens, right?
We're merchandisers. We carry inventory
and then deliver it to customers. We're
not trying to take the the we're not
disagreeing with customers. We're we're
providing a service. Mhm. And then on
the investment side, what is out further
on the risk curve for you?
>> I mean, I think we've lost money in more
ways than anyone you've ever had on this
show.
>> Well, uh, collectively,
>> what is the nature of a of a of an
investment that doesn't pan out? Is it
just it's high risk and you know that
going in or Yeah.
>> Yeah. Well, there's a wide range.
Obviously, in our trading business, it's
really systematic. Um, we have an
amazing team. and we educate kids right
out of school into our model. It's
really rare that they would leave and be
able to do the same thing because it is
about the collective.
>> Um but interesting but we started a
whole bunch of other businesses of
course. So
>> Peak Six today based on what Eric was
saying in your previous interview, it's
a company of companies. Okay. So we have
started or bought and turned around
15ish companies at this point
>> and primarily in the backend technology
space in fintech definitely in insure
techch which is relatively new to us and
edutch. So um those are the biggest
risks we're taking and then fast forward
as we built those businesses over the
years we started uh an investing side of
the business which is quite large
>> because it's all AI stuff now
>> and we started early enough so it grew
really fast. We have some doozies. I
mean, I
>> I don't want to dwell on it.
>> Yeah. No, we'll refer we're this is this
is a call back to your previous uh
>> person in 2008. We had uh it was a good
year for us. Not because we were smart
and short the market.
>> Yeah.
>> Jenny was like, "Things are confusing.
We should be in cash." And we were. So,
I was lucky.
>> Well, she was right. Like the market
goes crazy and then we have a lot of
cash. Everybody starts knocking on your
door in the fall. And she's like, "Well,
why don't we do something good for
humanity? will do electric vehicles.
>> Sure.
>> So, we are early.
>> Yeah.
>> So, we interview two different people at
the time.
>> We're not investors at this point. We
are traders. So, it's two different
things. We are operators. I still don't
know if we're in. We're just
knuckleheads.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> We get two people.
>> We're going to interview the two
companies at the time. Yeah. One is this
PayPal guy who's trying to do it and the
other is the guy who was the chief
architect at BMW.
>> Yeah. The PayPal guy gets on the co on a
call with us
>> with you.
>> With me,
>> just to be clear, the guy
from this see where this is going.
>> Yes, you know where it's going.
>> I mean, if he's listen if he listens to
this, he'll I don't know if he'll
remember cuz I think he was stoned out
of his mind. Okay.
>> It was the worst presentation I've ever
heard.
>> Like this guy's never going to build a
car.
>> It wasn't about cars. It was about It
was about the the train.
>> He was talking about trains. trains from
like electromagnetic trains also be
useful. I was like,
>> "What the hell are we talking about?"
>> This is supposed to be a business
investment. I want to hear the business
pitch.
>> And the other person comes in buttoned
up, right? German engineer.
>> Yep.
>> Amazing.
>> I've built these my entire career.
>> 100%. We go with that person. And then 9
months later,
>> we find out that the one we invested in,
when it rains, the cars catch on fire
and explode.
>> Crazy.
>> Not a good one. Yeah, that's not a good
bad downside. Yeah.
>> Yeah, that makes a lot of sense. I think
a lot of investors have had to really
come around to the the the other pattern
of thinking. I know that's right some
investors that uh I mean even on the
other side I know I know an investor
that passed on Tesla
>> but not uh but not because Elon was
thinking too futuristic uh he was
thinking well all the cars are going to
be self-driving and no one's going to
need a car anymore so if this guy's just
building cars why should I invest in
this and uh and of course the it was
Tesla was going to be the one to do that
but that was too hard to predict and it
just gets very very hard when you think
that far out so walk me through a deal
that is in the wheelhouse house. Um,
what's the structure? Are you looking
for a particular vintage, an age, a size
of like, you know, meat on the bones of
the company? Um, and then what are you
looking to do? Because there's when when
you come into a new company, you can be
transforming the business with AI. You
can be uh focused on cost reduction,
back office rationalization. Like
there's so many different techniques
that you can use to drive value.
>> Yeah. I'll I'll start maybe I'll start
with peak six trials. So at its core,
we're entrepreneurs, right? That's what
we do. So we're comfortable with that
risk. Ironically, it doesn't make us
super comfortable doing venture because
yeah, we're not doing it. Yeah. So we
have to find really special people.
We've been lucky in the universe of Peak
Six to have some of those special people
along the way. We just started something
called Peak Six Trials, which is an
think about entrepreneurship and
residents.
>> We have
>> it's you know like previous accelerators
>> except for that we have the capital.
It's already there. We have the
resources, the tech resources for
example, legal compliance, whatever it
is already there.
>> And then we also have the customers.
Yeah. Because of Apex FinTech solutions.
So that's our back-end tech
>> powers. Got it.
>> 40 million customers today. So end
consumers were B2B.
>> Yeah.
>> So there's a unique opportunity for
fintech and techch type of
>> young entrepreneurs who want to do
something. That's how we want to make
those bets.
>> Um that will go into our operating
company. sure
>> scenario and then I know you want to
talk about the investment side where we
take what kind of what kind of
investments we're looking for.
>> Yeah, sure.
>> Or even just the story of Apex. I'd love
to know like how how that came into the
portfolio, what the process was like.
That's I can tell it's already going to
be a good story.
>> Yeah. Uh so there was a public company
called Pensson. Yeah.
>> We owned and operated a brokerage called
Options House at the time. predates
Wealthfront Betterment and Robin Hood,
etc.
>> And that business custody, kept the
assets right at at Pensson along with a
million other customers, retail
customers. Um,
>> so we're in 2012 at this point.
>> Yes. And we get a call from the CEO of
the bank. This is the bank that holds
our money. Calls on a Friday. He's like,
"Hey, um, you guys have some money and
could you lend us some money for a
little bit?"
>> It would help us a lot.
>> Sure.
>> I'm like, "Let me think about I got to
talk to Jenny."
>> Yeah.
>> She's like, "We got to That's not a good
sign." Just
>> for your for your listeners or watch
your viewers, if your bank calls you and
asks to borrow more money, like that's
trouble.
>> Yeah.
>> So, s uh Monday morning, we get a call
from the SEC
There's fraud, announced fraud at the uh
at the clearing firm.
>> Wow.
>> And we want you to put $70 million into
the business by Friday.
>> Wow.
>> Or we're going to liquidate everybody.
>> And that's everybody in the market. So,
think pregeneration Robin Hood for
context. All those names out there,
those middle tier names besides the big
names. Yeah. Options. Our firm was one
of them. Sure.
>> They're all going to go.
>> Yeah.
>> So, 13 days later, we bought it.
>> Amazing.
>> Yeah. Announced fraud and all. That's
wild. Yeah. Yeah. I've heard a number of
these stories of like turning around a
company when there is fraud. I mean
Strauss Zelnik sort of did this with
Take Two is a fantastic turnaround of
that business. Uh it feels like an
incredible cultural challenge to
actually not just clean up the legal
documents and make this SEC happy with
whatever happened. It's actually a
cultural problem sometimes that led the
company down that path. That's right.
>> Uh how are you thinking about cultural
development generally? I feel like when
I when I dig into different funds,
there's fascinatingly different
approaches. You know, the the the Ray
Dalia is recording everything. There's
like so many different But you mentioned
that like when you train a new grad,
they come out with skills that are
uniquely uh just uh synergistic with the
rest of the firm. And so, how do you
think about uh the cultural values that
you want to instill in the next
generation? they are um they are
critical
>> really difficult in times of COVID and
changing work from home and all those
things and as we continue to build new
companies right so
>> um
>> you know at our firm that's over 28
years old they are ingrained it is um
>> a sense of urgency it's a work ethic
like it's it's just high and even when
the market is telling you you know we
ought to be different or nicer or
something like people are so engaged
It's it's really fun to be in the
markets. So, it makes that easy.
>> Um it's fun to be part of an
entrepreneurial culture. Yeah. So, that
makes that easy. So, how do I
>> And if you don't fit it actually they
weed out pretty quickly. We've had that
benefit over the years. But every time
we take on a new company, uh it is it is
a challenge for us to try and integrate
or have them stand in their own culture,
which is also fine with us, right? So if
we we sit at the top and we have CEOs of
each of these businesses, they are
dependent quite a bit on the the peak
six core because it's it's facilitating
the financial stuff. It's facilitating
the HR stuff.
>> And if they want to sort of ignore that
and not join the club,
>> it's it's it's a hard road because we've
figured out such a rhythm. When you get
in the rhythm, it makes each the
acceleration go so much faster. The
leverage we get with our people, with
the culture is just really exponential.
>> Yeah. Some people refer to it as like
you stress, the good type of stress.
Like it's a stressful scenario, but it
gives you energy. It doesn't actually
drain you. And I feel like if people
get, you know, the runner's high. So
running is very stressful for some
people, but for some people it's it's
invigorating. Uh, and I feel like if if
you know being in the market at a
tumultuous time gives you more energy
during that day, uh, that's something
where you'll probably thrive.
>> Yeah, I was going to say taking risk.
Yeah. Right. Starting as traders and
becoming operators and then investors
like at its core that that that trading
that heart and soul of trading and
taking risk every day, all day, getting
used to it, that isn't in everybody's
DNA.
>> Um,
>> it is part of the reason why we like
poker so much. We're trying trying to
teach a million girls and women to play
poker solely to get these male-dominated
areas for the women to feel more
welcome. But you have to be able to take
that risk every day.
>> And that and the organization thrives on
it. Yeah. Right. It's a little scary.
>> I know like 10 amazing female venture
investors and they're all incredible
poker players. Never sit down with them.
They would absolutely smoke me.
>> Well, the funny thing is I didn't play
all these years. Yeah. When I started to
play in 2019, it was a conversation we
had. It was about our daughter, etc. But
I realized I was like, "Wait, I've been
playing poker my whole career." Sure. I
just didn't know it.
>> Yeah.
>> It's the closest thing I'd ever seen to
options trading. Yeah.
>> So I was like, "Wait, is this what's
missing?" Because if we get who cares
how
>> people come into the puzzle, what the
more differentiated their backgrounds
are for us, right? If you look at 1997
and
>> he and I were partners. That's what, by
the way, we weren't married at the time.
We were together 10 years before we did.
go making that decision. That was a
highly unusual decision to me.
>> Chased me.
>> I love it. I love it.
>> You wish.
>> Uh, what are you looking for in a CEO?
If I want to come work for you and and
work for one of your portfolio
companies, what does it take to make it
as a CEO?
>> I don't think there's any like there's
no one thing. There's no prescriptive
formula. The number one thing we've
learned because we've look we've dealt
with thousands of employees,
CEOs, etc. invested in I don't know
hundreds not thousands of businesses.
>> Yeah.
>> Self-awareness is probably the most
important thing because what's going to
it can get you in trouble if you think
you're really smart like you
>> you better be really smart. What's p
poker teaches you a lot of that. That's
a good call back there for you. the uh
>> the
>> self-awareness like you control effort,
you control attitude. Those two things
you really do control like so hard work,
right? You're going to be positive
optimist
>> but awareness like
like hey we're the best.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, by the way, these other people
aren't that good. Like you should think
about it like constantly questioning
where you're at and being humble.
>> Yeah. Is is is self-awareness around
intelligence uh the main uh flaw for
CEOs or or are there CEOs that are
overconfident in their deal making
ability and their emotional intelligence
and their managerial ability and their
ability to public speak and do there's
so many different things. The CEO is a
bundle of traits. I I I feel like
intelligence is obviously super
important and making good strategic
decisions, executing, but there's so
much else that goes into actually
running a company.
>> I wouldn't say I would not say lack of
confidence is not necessarily an an
issue. Yeah. Overconfidence is disaster.
>> Interesting. Interesting.
>> You get yourself in a lot of trouble
because you know for sure that this is
going to happen. And when it doesn't,
>> you you're in a you're in a world of
hurt that happens. So, so what are the
signs that you're looking for to sus out
if someone is self-actualized in that
way? Aware of their their flaws, aware
of their strengths, their weaknesses.
How are you interrogating that in an
interview?
>> We hate interviews.
>> Okay. How do you recruit that?
>> Um, it's hard. It's hard. We've actually
tried to build tech over the years.
We've done all different things to try
and figure it out.
um we try and have without being
inefficient as long of a process as we
can
>> um to see somebody. So if we can
>> okay
>> get a student in December
>> for two two weeks during their break and
see them or we have a women's trading
experience that's eight weeks in the
summer. Anytime we get
>> an extension of time if we can I mean
the CEOs is is the hardest. We they
often come from within for us.
>> Sure.
>> Now some of our CEOs did not. Yeah. Um
but it is what our hit ratio I think on
just cold interview making it right I
think is really hard. So then of course
it's connections and recommendations and
all those things because you don't know
all of the different pieces of the
puzzle.
>> I think people get snowed all the time.
>> Yeah. Do you have a a bright line
between uh deal team, operating team
like those who evaluate a great company
to join the portfolio versus those who
will be going and operating the
businesses?
>> We have a very very small evaluating
team.
>> Okay.
>> Like this is the thing.
>> No, we have some really smart there's
some lawyers and some analysts in there.
Yeah.
>> But um at the end of the day, so we
don't have outside money.
>> Sure. So it's it's ours and then our
part our employees who have become
partners over the years. So that's who
we're investing on behalf
>> and um so but we are looking for any
guidance. We are just we know we're not
the smartest, right? That's what trading
does for you. It humbles you really
quickly. So
>> how do we connect? How do we partner
with great people on the outside and
then with the best people internally to
make a decision? But we're also willing
we're willing to take probably more risk
on average I would say with some of
these investments. I mean, we're not,
you know, on the energy side or on the
power side or on that that that
infrastructure side for us is new and
but we started early and we try and get
smart and try and be surrounded by
>> I want to get to energy. That sounds
fascinating. I want to first ask about
sourcing. Are are you close with a lot
of investment banks or are you cold
calling people saying I want to buy the
company like if you're into the deal
team? Uh where are the ideas coming
from? Mhm.
>> Yeah. I'd say the good ones come from
interpersonal
>> relations. Sure.
>> Which is why like in the age of AI and
everything's going to be automated,
everything like this really matters.
Showing up in a studio, we're you'll
hopefully send us, you know, you'll say,
"Hey, I have an idea for you guys."
>> That's what And vice versa, huh?
>> Yeah. Of course. Of course.
>> That I would say that's 99% of our
>> 99% of it. And but it's worked pretty
well.
>> That's so interesting. I mean, yeah, we
we we we talked to investors across the
category. There's some that are doing
tons of outbound. They have a price for
every company in their CRM. They have an
army of deal associates that are getting
out there pounding the pavement. There's
other folks who Yeah, just wildly
different strategies. It's fascinating.
>> Well, for being a very quiet firm for a
very long time,
>> um
>> it didn't allow us to have what we now
realize we probably should have been
doing for a while is building those
relationships. But it's been quick
coming out, like coming out um and
building those relationships and
figuring out how to make it work. We're
more mature doing it. We know what we're
looking for. Um
>> we made a [ __ ] ton of mistakes. So like,
>> you know, it's it's easy to start. You
know, they're not they're not perfect,
but they rhyme with the past, right? So,
um we're we're good at we're good at
saying no. Yeah, I would say.
>> Yeah. Uh let's talk about the energy
side. What's interesting there, it's a
very broad category. We talked to a
founder yesterday who's refining uranium
to go into nuclear power plants that
won't come online for five years on the
good side. Then at the same time, we
talked to uh you know Chase Lock Miller
from Crusoe. He's building data center
putting up power plants today. Uh
there's so many other pieces of
infrastructure, so many the supply chain
is so complicated. Where is the
opportunity?
>> You want to go ahead? Um, we like
Crusoe. We're investors in Cruso.
Really? Oh, yeah. No way. Oh, yeah.
That's amazing.
>> We've got a lot of investments. Okay.
Okay. And I like what is interesting in
energy is
>> it tends to be there. There's some
individuals or individual companies that
are doing some stuff that's that we see
as transformational. So, everybody's
very worried about energy.
>> Yeah.
>> Whatever happens with the war, we don't
have any thoughts on that.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> But assuming that things are peaceful
like, hey, is it going to be nuclear? or
is it going to be
>> solar?
>> Solar, etc. Um, geothermal is really
interesting. So, we're big investors in
a company called Fervo based in Utah.
It's um
>> your your viewers should look it up.
It's uh it's transformational and it's a
it's today.
>> So, it's built they're going to deliver
>> I don't know 500 megs in
>> Wow. That's a 2027.
>> Wow.
>> That's enough for That's the average
metac campus right now.
>> Okay. And remember, it's fracking.
traditional
>> drilling,
>> but not in traditional areas. Okay. So,
think more remote areas.
>> Sure.
>> Are there side effects? It's unclear. I
don't think there are necessarily, but
maybe there could be some seismic.
>> Um,
>> but like that's super interesting. And
the people who are doing that, like by
the way, there's plenty of heat down
there. It doesn't heat the planet.
There's a bunch of physics around that.
We're not physicists, but it won't make
the planet hotter.
>> Yeah. Because net zero.
>> Um, so that's a good one. I think
there's another company in Utah that we
like a lot. we were talking to him
earlier is Taurus energy
>> and that is what effectively what you
saw in cloud
>> uh compute is cloud energy and so Taurus
is a
>> it's basically a it's a flywheel
business like actually a flywheel
>> okay literal fly a literal flywheel
except it weighs about 3500 lb power
>> okay
>> but it spins remember the issue with
power is that it's
>> everybody draws at the same time if
you're snow basin in Utah and you draw
on power to run your tram at the same
time that everybody's hey by the way uh
open AI is going to run one of their
>> sure sure
>> uh you know one of their loops then
you're going to end up drawing tons of
power and that's expensive for the grid
>> so what
>> Nate has done and his team at at Taurus
is sol they're a balancer
>> the load balancer
>> it's the load balance and you realize
there's actually quite a bit of power
>> um how you actually balance the power is
is the hard part and he's solved it and
so they are operating uh operating ing
today. Um, we talked to him earlier.
He's he's in a bunch of different states
and he's he's coming to a state near
you.
>> Yeah. I love it. Uh, well, tell me more
about Peak Six Trials. Where can people
get started? How do people apply or or
join? How does this work?
>> So, peak6trials.com. Okay.
>> And we're looking for entrepreneurs who
have ideas. Cool. And everything else is
sort of there. You don't have to go and
raise money. You have to spend time
doing that. Think about the things that
>> where your specialty is is your idea.
Yeah. Right. This is this is a place
with AI like we can do a bunch of stuff
around you.
>> Yeah.
>> And interestingly like with Apex, right?
We have these 40 million customers. They
might want your product
>> and if they don't want your product
that's also really good news. So we
short circuit all these things that take
to say like is this a good idea or not?
You don't have to worry about the
capital. You don't have to worry about
paying your rent. We actually pay you
salary. No way. Yeah. So, um, it's
really nicely packaged for someone. I
wish we had it at the time. It would
have made me feel better. Yeah.
>> Um, maybe we were better off cuz
>> we took so much risk. You never know.
But the balance here is we want the
people who bring the ideas and we help
support and build it ultimately to own
the majority of thing, not for us to own
the majority of things. So, the the the
the
way we've structured the deals are
really creative, I think, and different
than the marketplace has seen so far. So
um
finding those people right those young
entrepreneurs or they may not be so
young entrepreneurs they can be anywhere
but it's really I mean I think it's
super broad yeah
>> what the fintech sort of space is like
everything's money every large
>> CPG company who has a bunch of customers
there's some money product that exists
or could exist in that ecosystem so
there's a lot of ideas I think that are
out there we're going to pick
>> 12 to 15 for the first year and we're
going to see what we can do and see what
we can pump through.
>> That's great. Last question. What's the
best way? I'm terrible at poker. What's
the best way for me to learn and get
better?
>> Well, we have amazing teachers around
the country, which is kind of crazy.
We're like at 28 teachers. We have
taught at like 360 companies. So, you
can actually bring us to your company.
Really? The banks, the technology firms,
the law firms.
>> I think they might like it. I think
these
>> It's been wild how people have picked it
up, right? Cuz first of all, we're not
playing for money. actually teaching
because these are people who know
nothing
>> but um
>> you know 94%
>> of poker players on the planet are men
so yes it's really extreme so I mean
after a couple hundred years of this
game coming around it's probably time
for women
>> to be doing this um we're in 70
countries we're in ro rural villages in
Kenya for example so
>> we are super quick turnkey events best
events that are on on the
>> poker power.comour.com.
I love it. Well, thank you both for
taking the time to come chat with us. Uh
we will close the show here on this
camera. Leave us five stars on Apple
Podcast and Spotify. Uh we'll be live
tomorrow at 11:00 a.m. Pacific sharp. Uh
sign up for our newsletter at tbpn.com
and we'll see you tomorrow. Goodbye.
Thank you.